<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-04-07T22:04:42-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">The Sujeeth Foundation</title><subtitle>Unlocking opportunity through education. The Sujeeth Foundation helps students network into their first job. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Announcing the Creation of Our GitHub Community</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/announcements/Github-Community/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Announcing the Creation of Our GitHub Community" /><published>2025-04-05T01:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-04-05T01:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/announcements/Github-Community</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/announcements/Github-Community/">&lt;p&gt;We are thrilled to announce the launch of our new &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SujeethFoundation/sujeethfoundation.github.io/wiki&quot;&gt;GitHub community&lt;/a&gt;! This platform is designed to bring together passionate individuals who are eager to collaborate, share knowledge, and contribute to our mission help unlock the opportunity of education for every college student.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;purpose-of-the-github-community&quot;&gt;Purpose of the GitHub Community&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our GitHub community aims to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Foster Collaboration&lt;/strong&gt;: By providing a space where members can share best practices, discuss challenges, and exchange resources, we hope to harness the power of collective wisdom.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Share Knowledge&lt;/strong&gt;: This community will serve as a repository of valuable insights, tutorials, and best practices that can help everyone improve their skills and knowledge.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Encourage Innovation&lt;/strong&gt;: We believe that by bringing together diverse perspectives, we can drive innovation and create solutions that make a real impact.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Support Our Mission&lt;/strong&gt;: Every contribution made in this community will directly support our mission of empowering students to take ownership of their career journey and achieve meaningful employment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-you-can-participate&quot;&gt;How You Can Participate&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We encourage everyone to get involved in our GitHub community. Here are a few ways you can participate:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Join Discussions&lt;/strong&gt;: Engage in conversations, ask questions, and share your insights on various topics.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Share Best Practices&lt;/strong&gt;: Contribute your experiences and strategies to help others succeed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discuss Challenges&lt;/strong&gt;: Openly discuss the challenges you face and collaborate with others to find solutions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Provide Resources&lt;/strong&gt;: Share valuable tools, articles, and resources that can benefit the community.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Offer Feedback&lt;/strong&gt;: Your feedback is crucial in helping us improve and evolve. Don’t hesitate to share your thoughts and suggestions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-your-participation-matters&quot;&gt;Why Your Participation Matters&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your involvement in our GitHub community is vital. By participating, you’re not only helping us achieve our mission but also contributing to a larger movement of collaboration and innovation. Together, we can create something truly remarkable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;key-sections&quot;&gt;Key Sections&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#program-overview&quot;&gt;Program Overview&lt;/a&gt;: Goals and structure of the Career Circle Program.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SujeethFoundation/sujeethfoundation.github.io/wiki/Best-Practices%3A&quot;&gt;Best Practices&lt;/a&gt;: Guidelines for mentors and strategies for student engagement.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#weekly-content&quot;&gt;Weekly Content&lt;/a&gt;: Detailed breakdown of each week’s objectives, agenda, and resources.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#additional-resources&quot;&gt;Additional Resources&lt;/a&gt;: Templates, videos, articles, and more.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SujeethFoundation/sujeethfoundation.github.io/discussions&quot;&gt;Discussion Board&lt;/a&gt;: Support and Best Practice Sharing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SujeethFoundation/sujeethfoundation.github.io/discussions&quot;&gt;University Circles Directory&lt;/a&gt;: Directory of LinkedIn Groups and weekly session recordings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;program-overview&quot; class=&quot;linked-heading&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;#program-overview&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt; Program Overview
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SujeethFoundation/sujeethfoundation.github.io/wiki/Program-Overview%3A&quot;&gt;wiki&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;objective&quot;&gt;Objective&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bridge the gap between higher education and meaningful employment for college students.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Empower students to take ownership of their career journey through mentorship and practical guidance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;structure&quot;&gt;Structure&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Week 1:&lt;/strong&gt; Self-Assessment&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Week 2:&lt;/strong&gt; Research &amp;amp; Exploration&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Week 3:&lt;/strong&gt; Resume &amp;amp; Preparation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Week 4:&lt;/strong&gt; Networking&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Week 5:&lt;/strong&gt; Applications &amp;amp; Interviews&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Week 6:&lt;/strong&gt; Follow-up &amp;amp; Negotiation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;key-concepts&quot;&gt;Key Concepts&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vulnerability and Trust&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Grit and Perseverance&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Purpose-Driven Approach&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Working Out Loud&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lean Startup Methodology&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Power of Appreciation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Learning from Regret&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;goals&quot;&gt;Goals&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reduce underemployment among graduates.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Maximize return on educational investment.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Foster genuine workplace engagement and satisfaction.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Equip students with tools and mindset for successful career navigation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;weekly-content&quot; class=&quot;linked-heading&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;#weekly-content&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt; Weekly Content
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SujeethFoundation/sujeethfoundation.github.io/wiki/Weekly-Content%3A&quot;&gt;wiki&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;week-1-self-assessment&quot;&gt;Week 1: Self-Assessment&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;objective-1&quot;&gt;Objective:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understand your strengths, goals, and areas of growth to make better career decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;agenda&quot;&gt;Agenda:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Introductions and Icebreaker: Get to know your peers and mentors.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Brené Brown Interview Clip: Discuss vulnerability and building trust in professional settings.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Exercise - Build Your Coat of Arms: Reflect on your personal and professional journey.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Group Discussion: Focus on vulnerability, personal stories, and trust-building.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;week-2-research--exploration&quot;&gt;Week 2: Research &amp;amp; Exploration&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;objective-2&quot;&gt;Objective:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn how to explore industries, roles, and companies that align with your goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;agenda-1&quot;&gt;Agenda:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Group Reflection: Discuss strategies for exploring job opportunities.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Video: Identifying Your Career Path: Understanding your values and aligning them with career choices.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Exercise: Research companies and roles to identify your fit.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Group Discussion: Share insights and challenges in the exploration process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;week-3-resume--preparation&quot;&gt;Week 3: Resume &amp;amp; Preparation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;objective-3&quot;&gt;Objective:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Develop a strong base resume and optimize your LinkedIn profile for job applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;agenda-2&quot;&gt;Agenda:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Group Reflection: Discuss resume tailoring and challenges faced.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Video: Building a Strong Base Resume: Learn best practices for crafting a resume.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Exercise: Create or Update LinkedIn Profile: Align your online presence with your resume.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Group Discussion: Share tips and strategies for a standout resume and profile.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;week-4-networking&quot;&gt;Week 4: Networking&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;objective-4&quot;&gt;Objective:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Build a professional network through genuine relationships and effective strategies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;agenda-3&quot;&gt;Agenda:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Group Reflection: Discuss the challenges and strategies for networking.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Video: Working Out Loud: Learn to build meaningful relationships by helping others.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Exercise: ChatGPT Follow Leaders: Identify key thought leaders to connect with.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Group Discussion: Share experiences and strategies for successful networking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;week-5-applications--interviews&quot;&gt;Week 5: Applications &amp;amp; Interviews&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;objective-5&quot;&gt;Objective:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Refine your job search strategy and improve interview storytelling techniques.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;agenda-4&quot;&gt;Agenda:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Group Reflection: Discuss job application strategies and the importance of “Start with Why”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Video: How Many Jobs Should I Apply to?: Explore the balance between quantity and quality in job applications.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Exercise: Storytelling During Interviews: Learn how to effectively communicate your experiences.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Group Discussion: Share interview tips and challenges faced.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;week-6-follow-up--negotiation&quot;&gt;Week 6: Follow-up &amp;amp; Negotiation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;objective-6&quot;&gt;Objective:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Master the art of following up after interviews and learn negotiation strategies for job offers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;agenda-5&quot;&gt;Agenda:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Group Reflection: Discuss follow-up strategies and how they influence decision-making.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Video: Ultimate Guide to Following Up: Learn best practices for following up after interviews.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Video: The Power of Regret by Daniel Pink: Explore how regret can influence decisions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Group Discussion: Reflect on follow-up challenges and strategies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;additional-resources&quot; class=&quot;linked-heading&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;#additional-resources&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt; Additional Resources
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SujeethFoundation/sujeethfoundation.github.io/wiki/Additional-Resources%3A&quot;&gt;wiki&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;exercise-build-your-coat-of-arms&quot;&gt;Exercise: Build Your Coat of Arms&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This exercise helps students gain clarity about their strengths and direction. It sets the foundation for a focused job search and helps them make decisions based on self-understanding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;principle-self-awareness-leads-to-clarity&quot;&gt;Principle: Self-awareness leads to clarity.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By understanding where they’ve been and where they want to go, students can set a course for the future that aligns with their values and goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;video-dare-to-lead-brené-brown-interview&quot;&gt;Video: “Dare to Lead” Brené Brown Interview&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This video inspires students to embrace vulnerability in their professional journey, encouraging them to be authentic and trust-building in their job search and career development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;principle-vulnerability-builds-trust-and-connection&quot;&gt;Principle: Vulnerability builds trust and connection.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leaders and professionals who are open, authentic, and vulnerable tend to build stronger relationships and are better at influencing others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;video-how-to-find-your-purpose&quot;&gt;Video: How to Find Your Purpose&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Helping students discover their purpose ensures they pursue careers that align with their personal values and passions, resulting in more fulfilling work and sustained motivation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;principle-purpose-fuels-motivation-and-direction&quot;&gt;Principle: Purpose fuels motivation and direction.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding one’s purpose is key to finding career satisfaction and achieving long-term success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;exercise-brainstorm-career-path-with-chatgpt&quot;&gt;Exercise: Brainstorm Career Path with ChatGPT&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This exercise empowers students to think broadly about their career options and helps them identify paths that align with their aspirations, increasing the likelihood of long-term success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;principle-exploration-leads-to-informed-decision-making&quot;&gt;Principle: Exploration leads to informed decision-making.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By exploring various options, students gain insights into possible career paths they may not have considered otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;video-connect-with-hiring-managers&quot;&gt;Video: Connect with Hiring Managers&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ability to connect with hiring managers is a valuable skill in a competitive job market. This content helps students understand how to approach these professionals and build lasting relationships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;principle-networking-is-about-building-relationships-not-just-seeking-opportunities&quot;&gt;Principle: Networking is about building relationships, not just seeking opportunities.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building authentic connections with hiring managers can open doors and help students stand out in the job market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;video-the-origin-of-why&quot;&gt;Video: The Origin of Why&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This video helps students identify their core purpose, which is crucial for personal and professional alignment. It also serves as a foundation for crafting meaningful resumes and LinkedIn profiles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;principle-clarity-of-purpose-guides-actions&quot;&gt;Principle: Clarity of purpose guides actions.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When students understand their “why,” they can make decisions that align with their core values and goals, leading to more authentic career paths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;video-build-a-strong-base-resume&quot;&gt;Video: Build a Strong Base Resume&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A resume is the cornerstone of a job application. This content helps students present themselves professionally and ensures their resume is aligned with industry expectations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;principle-preparation-is-key-to-presenting-yourself-effectively&quot;&gt;Principle: Preparation is key to presenting yourself effectively.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A strong, well-crafted resume is the first step in catching a recruiter’s attention and landing interviews.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;video-build-a-linkedin-profile&quot;&gt;Video: Build a LinkedIn Profile&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a vital component of any job search, a strong LinkedIn profile helps students network, connect with recruiters, and showcase their experience in an easily accessible way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;principle-your-online-presence-matters&quot;&gt;Principle: Your online presence matters.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An optimized LinkedIn profile is a powerful tool for job seekers to connect with professionals, showcase their skills, and build credibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;video-working-out-loud-with-john-stepper&quot;&gt;Video: Working Out Loud with John Stepper&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Working Out Loud” encourages students to engage with their professional community by contributing and sharing, fostering strong relationships that can aid in career growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;principle-transparency-builds-trust-and-relationships&quot;&gt;Principle: Transparency builds trust and relationships.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By openly sharing progress and offering support to others, students can build their network and demonstrate thought leadership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;video-10-ways-to-contribute&quot;&gt;Video: 10 Ways to Contribute&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contributing to the community is an effective way to grow one’s network and establish a professional reputation. This video empowers students to actively engage and provide value in their networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;principle-contributing-adds-value-to-both-you-and-others&quot;&gt;Principle: Contributing adds value to both you and others.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The act of contributing not only helps others but also strengthens the student’s professional profile and reputation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;exercise-chatgpt-follow-leaders&quot;&gt;Exercise: ChatGPT Follow Leaders&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This exercise helps students identify individuals who can support their professional development and guides them in establishing connections that may be crucial for their career growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;principle-engagement-with-thought-leaders-enhances-learning-and-networking&quot;&gt;Principle: Engagement with thought leaders enhances learning and networking.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connecting with industry leaders and influencers provides students with insights and opens doors for new opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;video-branding-yourself-through-social-media&quot;&gt;Video: Branding Yourself Through Social Media&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In today’s digital world, a strong social media brand is essential for networking and job searching. This video teaches students how to use social media to support their professional goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;principle-your-personal-brand-shapes-how-others-perceive-you&quot;&gt;Principle: Your personal brand shapes how others perceive you.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Social media is an extension of your professional identity, and managing it carefully helps students build credibility and influence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;video-how-many-jobs-should-i-apply-to&quot;&gt;Video: How Many Jobs Should I Apply To?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This content helps students avoid the trap of applying to too many jobs without a strategy, encouraging them to focus their efforts on high-quality opportunities that align with their goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;principle-quality-over-quantity-in-job-applications&quot;&gt;Principle: Quality over quantity in job applications.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A focused approach is more effective than applying indiscriminately. Tailoring applications ensures better chances of success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;video-storytelling-during-the-interview&quot;&gt;Video: Storytelling During the Interview&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Storytelling is a key skill in interviews. This video teaches students how to craft compelling stories that demonstrate their capabilities and make a lasting impression on interviewers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;principle-storytelling-builds-a-compelling-narrative&quot;&gt;Principle: Storytelling builds a compelling narrative.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Effective storytelling makes students’ experiences more memorable and helps interviewers see how their skills and values align with the role.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;video-the-lean-startup-book-summary&quot;&gt;Video: The Lean Startup Book Summary&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This content helps students understand the value of failure as a learning opportunity, reinforcing the idea of constant iteration and improvement in their job search and career development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;principle-failure-is-part-of-the-process-and-learning-is-continuous&quot;&gt;Principle: Failure is part of the process, and learning is continuous.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lean Startup methodology encourages experimentation and iterative learning, which are essential for improving one’s job search approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;video-ultimate-guide-to-following-up&quot;&gt;Video: Ultimate Guide to Following Up&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following up is often overlooked but crucial for making a lasting impression. This content teaches students how to stay top of mind after an interview and improve their chances of success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;principle-follow-up-demonstrates-professionalism-and-persistence&quot;&gt;Principle: Follow-up demonstrates professionalism and persistence.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Effective follow-up can make the difference between getting the job or being overlooked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;video-daniel-pink-on-the-power-of-regret&quot;&gt;Video: Daniel Pink on the Power of Regret&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This video helps students reflect on their past decisions and use those insights to make better, more informed choices in their future careers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;principle-regret-provides-valuable-lessons-for-decision-making&quot;&gt;Principle: Regret provides valuable lessons for decision-making.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By acknowledging and understanding regret, students can make more informed, aligned decisions in their careers.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="announcements" /><summary type="html">The Sujeeth Foundation Github Community brings together career mentors to share knowledge. Key Sections include Career Circle Program Structure and Weekly Agenda&apos;s. There&apos;s even an inventory of content that clearly explains the purpose behind the content.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Adaptability: Michelle Leaverton</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Michelle-Leaverton/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Adaptability: Michelle Leaverton" /><published>2025-03-06T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2025-03-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Michelle-Leaverton</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Michelle-Leaverton/">&lt;p&gt;The Sujeeth Foundation Spotlight highlights the stories of individuals who made the jump from academia to industry.  We share stories to inspire and educate.  We hope students can leverage this experience in their own journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some career paths are straightforward, while others, like Michelle Leaverton’s, weave through diverse industries and experiences, culminating in a skillset that defies categorization. From corporate project management to nonprofit leadership and ministry, Michelle’s journey exemplifies resilience, adaptability, and a deep commitment to making an impact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-career-spanning-corporate-nonprofit-and-religious-sectors&quot;&gt;A Career Spanning Corporate, Nonprofit, and Religious Sectors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Michelle’s professional story is one of transformation and versatility. She recently held a role as an Advisor in Project and Program Management at Dell Technologies, where she worked in the Global Presales PMO. Over 2.5 years, she spearheaded global-scale enablement programs, process improvements, and career development initiatives for a workforce of over 5,000 professionals. Her ability to drive complex projects with creativity and collaboration made her an invaluable asset to the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before Dell, Michelle dedicated much of her career to nonprofit and ministry work, reflecting her passion for community engagement and social impact. She served as the Youth and Social Impact Director at Westminster Presbyterian Church, where she designed and managed youth programs, mission trips, and outreach initiatives addressing food insecurity, homelessness, and immigrant support. Her leadership in coordinating volunteers for Meals on Wheels during the pandemic further demonstrated her ability to mobilize communities in times of need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-new-chapter-entrepreneurship-and-communication-expertise&quot;&gt;A New Chapter: Entrepreneurship and Communication Expertise&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In August 2024, Michelle launched Collateral Designs, a business specializing in polished presentations and impactful communications. Her firm offers services that enhance clarity, creativity, and professionalism in business materials—helping clients craft compelling messages and visuals that stand out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Michelle’s expertise in communication, project development, and strategic planning positions her uniquely at the intersection of corporate efficiency and nonprofit passion. She holds a Bachelor of Arts in Russian Studies and Environmental Studies from the University of Kansas and a Master of Arts in Christian Education from Union Presbyterian Seminary. Her diverse academic background underscores her ability to think across disciplines and adapt to new challenges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;resilience-through-lifes-challenges&quot;&gt;Resilience Through Life’s Challenges&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond her professional achievements, Michelle’s personal journey is marked by resilience and growth. She and her husband, Rod, have spent the past decade rebuilding their lives after the loss of their first spouses to cancer. Through grief and joy, they’ve forged a new path, embracing life with their blended family and continuing to make a difference in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bringing-fresh-perspectives-to-every-opportunity&quot;&gt;Bringing Fresh Perspectives to Every Opportunity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether managing global programs, leading nonprofit initiatives, or helping businesses refine their messaging, Michelle Leaverton approaches every challenge with a problem-solving mindset. Her ability to adapt, learn, and lead across sectors is a testament to the power of a diverse career path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking for someone who can blend corporate strategy with a heart for mission-driven work, Michelle is a name to remember.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’d love to spot light you.  Tell us your story at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sujeeth.org/stories&quot;&gt;https://www.sujeeth.org/stories&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="spotlight" /><summary type="html">Michelle Leaverton showcased her resilience and adaptability as she transitioned from corporate project management at Dell Technologies to nonprofit leadership and ministry, and eventually launched her own business, Collateral Designs. Discover practical tips for students on building experience, embracing challenges, and making a positive impact in their professional lives.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Prepare and Adapt: Dave D’Abate</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Dave-Dabate/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Prepare and Adapt: Dave D’Abate" /><published>2025-03-06T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2025-03-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Dave-Dabate</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Dave-Dabate/">&lt;p&gt;The Sujeeth Foundation Spotlight highlights the stories of individuals who made the jump from academia to industry.  We share stories to inspire and educate.  We hope students can leverage this experience in their own journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For college juniors preparing to launch their careers, the path ahead can feel both exciting and uncertain. How do you land that first job? What skills truly matter? How do you turn a job into a fulfilling career? To help answer these questions, we spoke with Dave D’Abate, a successful Account Executive whose career journey is proof that relationships, continuous learning, and adaptability are key ingredients for long-term success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;starting-strong-lessons-from-the-first-job&quot;&gt;Starting Strong: Lessons from the First Job&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dave’s career began at AT&amp;amp;T as a retail sales consultant. Like many fresh graduates, he started in an entry-level role, selling devices and services to both consumers and small business accounts. But what set him apart? His mindset. While others simply met expectations, Dave aimed higher—doubling his sales targets and positioning himself as a go-to resource and subject matter expert.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He quickly learned that success isn’t just about showing up; it’s about being proactive. “I had to put in the effort beyond what I witnessed from my colleagues,” he says. This willingness to go the extra mile became a defining trait in his career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;breaking-into-the-workforce-the-power-of-first-impressions&quot;&gt;Breaking into the Workforce: The Power of First Impressions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Landing that first job can be daunting, but Dave emphasizes the importance of energy, enthusiasm, and preparation. One piece of advice he received early on has stuck with him: “Every conversation you have is an interview.” From the very first screening call to the final handshake, the way you present yourself matters. Being able to articulate your work ethic and passion can make all the difference in standing out to hiring managers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;building-a-career-key-lessons-and-mindset-shifts&quot;&gt;Building a Career: Key Lessons and Mindset Shifts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the years, Dave has picked up several insights that have fueled his success:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be willing to learn.&lt;/strong&gt; Taking the extra time to do something correctly now will set you up for success later.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Manage your business.&lt;/strong&gt; If something needs to get done, schedule time for it—otherwise, it won’t happen.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adaptability is key.&lt;/strong&gt; You won’t always succeed on the first try, but the ability to adjust and improve will make you stronger.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incorporate feedback immediately.&lt;/strong&gt; When someone offers guidance, show them that their investment in you is worth it by implementing changes right away.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;from-college-to-career-the-importance-of-preparation&quot;&gt;From College to Career: The Importance of Preparation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dave admits that he wasn’t the best student in college—he spent more time hiking than studying. But he quickly realized that preparation is everything. “Studying in college is very similar to how one should prepare before any meeting,” he explains. Whether it’s a class or a client presentation, showing up unprepared is never an option. Observing how others operate and borrowing their best practices can help you refine your own approach over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;final-advice-for-students-entering-the-workforce&quot;&gt;Final Advice for Students Entering the Workforce&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dave’s parting wisdom for students is simple yet powerful: “Always set aside time to continue investing in your success.” Seek out mentors who are invested in your growth, absorb their knowledge, and apply it. But never stop learning—if you ever find yourself as the smartest person in the room, it’s time to find a different room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you chart your own career path, remember that success isn’t a straight line. It’s built on hard work, adaptability, and the relationships you nurture along the way. Take a page from Dave D’Abate’s journey, and embrace every opportunity to learn and grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’d love to spot light you.  Tell us your story at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sujeeth.org/stories&quot;&gt;https://www.sujeeth.org/stories&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="spotlight" /><summary type="html">Dave D&apos;Abate relied on relationships, continuous learning, and adaptability to go from retail sales consultant at AT&amp;T to Account Executive. Discover practical tips for students on building experience, embracing challenges, and navigating their career paths effectively.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Stepping Stones: Will Kyle</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Will-Kyle/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Stepping Stones: Will Kyle" /><published>2025-03-06T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2025-03-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Will-Kyle</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Will-Kyle/">&lt;p&gt;The Sujeeth Foundation Spotlight highlights the stories of individuals who made the jump from academia to industry.  We share stories to inspire and educate.  We hope students can leverage this experience in their own journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Navigating a career path can be daunting for college juniors looking ahead to life after graduation. With uncertainty, competition, and the challenge of finding the right fit, it’s easy to feel overwhelmed. But stories of success can inspire and guide us—and Will Kyle’s journey from an entry-level sales job to leading a team at Amazon Web Services (AWS) is one of perseverance, adaptability, and growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#Starting Out: The First Job That Built a Foundation
Will Kyle’s first job out of college was far from glamorous—selling steel buildings. It wasn’t his dream job, nor was it in an industry he was particularly passionate about, but it was an opportunity to gain experience, develop his skills, and prove himself in the professional world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time, the economy was in a recession, making job opportunities scarce. Will applied to any and every sales role he could find. After spotting an ad online for a steel building company, he took the leap. His role involved managing a network of steel building dealers, prospecting new customers, and running advertising campaigns. The company was resistant to technology, forcing him to work without the efficiencies of modern tools. Yet, instead of seeing this as a setback, he saw it as a learning experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With no structured training in sales, Will took ownership of his own professional development. He read books, sought mentorship, and pushed himself out of his comfort zone. The key lesson? Success is rarely handed to you—it’s something you must actively pursue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;climbing-the-ladder-wills-career-at-amazon-and-aws&quot;&gt;Climbing the Ladder: Will’s Career at Amazon and AWS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will’s persistence and commitment to learning paved the way for his entry into major corporate roles. He spent have spent 12 years at Amazon, 8 years in ecommerce and 4 years at AWS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, as an Enterprise Sales Leader at AWS, Will is responsible for business planning, consultative selling, and leading high-impact initiatives. Over the past four years at AWS, he has excelled in multiple roles, including Senior Account Executive, where he leveraged his deep expertise in sales presentations and strategic client engagement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His career at AWS has given him the opportunity to lead a team of professionals, drive enterprise growth, and work at the cutting edge of cloud technology. Most importantly, he has continued to develop his passion for mentorship—helping individuals advance their careers both within and outside of Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lessons-from-the-journey-building-a-network-and-asking-for-help&quot;&gt;Lessons from the Journey: Building a Network and Asking for Help&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reflecting on his career, Will emphasizes the importance of networking and mentorship. “Every single person you meet is an opportunity to expand your network. Never burn a bridge,” he advises. Throughout his career, he has found that there are always people willing to help—but it’s up to you to ask for guidance. Taking initiative in building relationships and seeking mentorship can be game-changing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;advice-for-college-juniors-the-first-job-is-just-a-stepping-stone&quot;&gt;Advice for College Juniors: The First Job is Just a Stepping Stone&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For college juniors about to embark on their professional journeys, Will offers one crucial piece of advice: Be patient and focus on building experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your first job out of school doesn’t have to be your dream job. It’s a stepping stone—a chance to learn, build skills, and prove yourself to future employers. Instead of limiting yourself to roles that seem perfect, embrace opportunities that allow you to grow. Your passions and goals will evolve over time, and the most important thing is to keep moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will Kyle’s career path is a testament to the power of resilience, continuous learning, and strategic networking. Whether you’re a college junior trying to find direction or an early-career professional seeking motivation, his story serves as a reminder that every experience—no matter how small—can be a building block for future success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay open to opportunities, invest in relationships, and never stop learning. Your journey is just beginning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’d love to spot light you.  Tell us your story at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sujeeth.org/stories&quot;&gt;https://www.sujeeth.org/stories&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="spotlight" /><summary type="html">Will Kyle shares how perseverance, mentorship, and strategic networking helped him navigate challenges and achieve success in his journey from selling steel buildings to becoming an Enterprise Sales Leader at AWS. Learn practical tips for students on building experience, embracing opportunities, and making the most of their first job.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Start Small: Laurel Dzneladze</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Laurel-Dzneladze/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Start Small: Laurel Dzneladze" /><published>2025-03-06T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2025-03-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Laurel-Dzneladze</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Laurel-Dzneladze/">&lt;p&gt;The Sujeeth Foundation Spotlight highlights the stories of individuals who made the jump from academia to industry.  We share stories to inspire and educate.  We hope students can leverage this experience in their own journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Planning your career might seem daunting, but learning from those who have navigated similar paths can be both inspiring and insightful. One such story is that of Laurel Dzneladze, a dynamic professional at Microsoft whose journey showcases the power of adaptability, networking, and continuous learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;finding-passion-through-experience&quot;&gt;Finding Passion Through Experience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Laurel currently supports the Microsoft Viva Community and communication products, focusing on product marketing and go-to-market strategies. Her passion lies in how community and communications shape an organization’s success. Throughout her career, she has dedicated herself to building solutions that drive engagement, productivity, and overall success within companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her career trajectory wasn’t a straight line, but each experience helped shape her professional path. Laurel’s story is proof that discovering your Ikigai—the intersection of passion, mission, vocation, and profession—takes time, experimentation, and a willingness to explore different opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;from-internship-to-full-time-success&quot;&gt;From Internship to Full-Time Success&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Laurel’s first job came as an extension of an internship at Johnson Controls, which transitioned into a full-time role after graduation. In this position, she was responsible for communicating large organizational changes and managing digital spaces like the company’s website and intranet.
Some of her most valuable lessons from this early experience included:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Understanding organizational processes&lt;/strong&gt;—how to start and complete a project effectively.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Developing presentation and executive relationship skills&lt;/strong&gt;—key abilities that help in gaining visibility and trust.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Collaborating in a corporate environment&lt;/strong&gt;—learning how to navigate teams and work cross-functionally.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;landing-the-first-job-a-lesson-in-proactive-networking&quot;&gt;Landing the First Job: A Lesson in Proactive Networking&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How did Laurel secure her internship that led to her first job? It started with an unpaid marketing role at a performing arts foundation, where she dedicated just four hours a week. That experience gave her exposure to a network of professionals, including board members who later connected her with the internship opportunity at Johnson Controls.
Her journey highlights a crucial strategy:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Start small, be proactive, and leverage networking opportunities. Even the smallest roles can lead to significant career breakthroughs when approached with the right mindset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;career-lessons-and-mindset-shifts&quot;&gt;Career Lessons and Mindset Shifts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout her career, Laurel has embraced a mindset of continuous learning and adaptability. Here are some of her key insights:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Share ideas early and often&lt;/strong&gt;—don’t be afraid to put your thoughts out there.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ask questions instead of disagreeing outright&lt;/strong&gt;—a great approach to constructive discussions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Observe and learn from leadership&lt;/strong&gt;—find role models whose work ethic and leadership style resonate with you.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Look beyond your immediate team&lt;/strong&gt;—seek projects outside your role that expose you to new challenges and learning opportunities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;embracing-a-nonlinear-path&quot;&gt;Embracing a Nonlinear Path&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Laurel’s college experience was anything but conventional. She started as a dance major in Kansas City, studied abroad for a year, then took time off before resuming college at 25 years old. She compressed 2.5 years of coursework into just 1.5 years, proving that determination and flexibility can reshape one’s academic and career path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This unconventional journey reinforced an important lesson: careers are not always linear. The skills and experiences you gain from varied paths can become assets in unexpected ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;advice-for-college-students&quot;&gt;Advice for College Students&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If Laurel could give one piece of advice to students entering the workforce, it would be:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Not every role needs to be your dream job, and not every company needs to be your dream company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s okay to change your mind about your career direction multiple times. What matters is gaining clarity on what excites you and where you want to grow after spending time in the workforce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Takeaways for Your Career Journey
Laurel Dzneladze’s story is a testament to the power of &lt;strong&gt;persistence, adaptability, and strategic networking&lt;/strong&gt;. Whether you’re just starting out or rethinking your path, remember that &lt;strong&gt;every experience adds value&lt;/strong&gt;—even the unexpected ones. Your journey is uniquely yours, and with an open mind and proactive approach, you can carve a fulfilling and successful career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s your next step?&lt;/strong&gt; Start small, be open to opportunities, and don’t be afraid to take the unconventional path—it might just lead you exactly where you need to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’d love to spot light you.  Tell us your story at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sujeeth.org/stories&quot;&gt;https://www.sujeeth.org/stories&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="spotlight" /><summary type="html">Laurel Dzneladze leveraged adaptability, networking, and continuous learning to go from an unpaid marketing role to a full-time position at Johnson Controls. Discover practical tips for students on building experience, embracing challenges, and navigating their career paths effectively.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Find Your Why: Valerie Bergman</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Valerie-Bergman/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Find Your Why: Valerie Bergman" /><published>2025-03-06T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2025-03-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Valerie-Bergman</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Valerie-Bergman/">&lt;p&gt;The Sujeeth Foundation Spotlight highlights the stories of individuals who made the jump from academia to industry.  We share stories to inspire and educate.  We hope students can leverage this experience in their own journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As students begin to navigate the bridge between academics and career aspirations, it can feel like an overwhelming journey. Questions about the right first job, long-term goals, and personal fulfillment often weigh heavily on students. That’s why we’re thrilled to spotlight &lt;strong&gt;Valerie Bergman&lt;/strong&gt;, a Field Sales Specialist for Data and AI in Azure at Microsoft, whose career journey offers both inspiration and practical advice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Valerie Bergman’s career spans over 20 years, from starting as a software engineer to becoming a Data &amp;amp; AI Specialist at Microsoft. Along the way, she led IT strategy at Avtex Solutions, guided enterprise customers as a technology strategist, and now helps businesses innovate with AI and data solutions. Her journey reflects a focus on solving problems, driving innovation, and mentoring future STEM leaders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;aligning-passion-with-profession&quot;&gt;Aligning Passion with Profession&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Valerie’s current role at Microsoft combines her technical expertise with her passion for helping others. She thrives on solving complex problems and helping her customers justify their investments in innovation. Her journey exemplifies the Japanese concept of &lt;strong&gt;Ikigai&lt;/strong&gt;, or “reason for being,” as she’s managed to align her passion, mission, vocation, and profession.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Valerie’s story is a testament to the importance of finding work that resonates deeply with your skills and values. She believes that career success isn’t just about the “how” but about understanding the “&lt;strong&gt;why&lt;/strong&gt;”—a lesson that has guided her throughout her career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-first-career-step&quot;&gt;The First Career Step&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Valerie’s career began as a software engineer for a consulting company, where she developed custom software. This experience was pivotal in shaping her career trajectory. “I learned so much about technology in school, but my first job kickstarted my passion for understanding business requirements and opportunities,” Valerie recalls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of her key takeaways from this early experience was the importance of focusing on &lt;strong&gt;why, who, and what&lt;/strong&gt; before jumping into the &lt;strong&gt;how&lt;/strong&gt;. “Too often, failure happens because the ‘why’ is not fully understood,” she notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;strategies-that-work&quot;&gt;Strategies That Work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Landing her first job was no accident. Valerie credits a combination of &lt;strong&gt;networking&lt;/strong&gt;, building an &lt;strong&gt;online brand&lt;/strong&gt;, and leveraging &lt;strong&gt;job postings&lt;/strong&gt; as strategies that helped her break into the tech industry. Her experience underscores the importance of being proactive and using multiple approaches when job hunting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lessons-from-the-journey&quot;&gt;Lessons from the Journey&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Valerie’s career journey has been shaped by valuable insights and mindset shifts, such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Always seek to understand &lt;strong&gt;why&lt;/strong&gt; before tackling how.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t shy away from failure; view it as a stepping stone, not a permanent setback.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keep learning and stay curious.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;college-experience-a-foundation-for-growth&quot;&gt;College Experience: A Foundation for Growth&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Valerie, college wasn’t just about academics—it was also about preparing for the real world. While working her way through school, she developed critical time-management skills and gained early career exposure. However, Valerie also emphasizes the importance of engaging with the &lt;strong&gt;social aspects of college life&lt;/strong&gt;, as these experiences help build networks and develop interpersonal skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;words-of-wisdom-for-the-next-generation&quot;&gt;Words of Wisdom for the Next Generation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Valerie’s advice for students is both simple and profound:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Always have fun.&lt;/strong&gt; Find joy in what you do, no matter where you are in your career.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be courageous.&lt;/strong&gt; Take risks and lean into challenges.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Never compromise who you are.&lt;/strong&gt; Authenticity is key to long-term success.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-final-thought&quot;&gt;A Final Thought&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Valerie Bergman’s journey shows that a fulfilling career is about more than just landing a job—it’s about aligning your skills, passions, and values. For college juniors planning their futures, her story serves as a powerful reminder to focus on the “why” behind their career choices, embrace continuous learning, and take bold steps toward their goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let Valerie’s advice be your guide as you embark on your career journey—and remember, every failed attempt is simply a stepping stone toward success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’d love to spot light you.  Tell us your story at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sujeeth.org/stories&quot;&gt;https://www.sujeeth.org/stories&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="spotlight" /><summary type="html">Valerie Bergman aligned passion with profession, strategic networking, and continuous learning on her inspiring journey from software engineer to Microsoft Field Sales Specialist. Get practical advice on building experience, embracing challenges, and staying authentic.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Yes Now, Learn It Later: Britt Hall</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Britt-Hall/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Yes Now, Learn It Later: Britt Hall" /><published>2025-03-06T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2025-03-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Britt-Hall</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Britt-Hall/">&lt;p&gt;The Sujeeth Foundation Spotlight highlights the stories of individuals who made the jump from academia to industry.  We share stories to inspire and educate.  We hope students can leverage this experience in their own journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For many college juniors, the uncertainty of what comes next can be overwhelming. You might be wondering if your major is the right fit, how to land your first job, or whether the twists and turns of your journey will lead to success. To offer some inspiration, we’re sharing the story of Britt Hall—a professional who carved out a fulfilling career by embracing change, saying “yes” to opportunities, and staying true to their values.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Britt Hall’s career has been a journey of transformation, adaptability, and storytelling. She began in journalism, leading student newspapers and shaping narratives that connected communities. That passion for communication and culture led her into corporate environments, where she built internal communications strategies, fostered engagement, and helped organizations navigate change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Whole Foods Market, Britt played a key role in launching the 365 brand, designing team member experiences and driving internal culture. At National Instruments, she partnered with senior leaders to implement large-scale transformation and modern workplace initiatives. Now, at Cisco, she leads global enablement efforts, ensuring talent strategies empower people and teams to thrive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through every step, Britt’s work has been shaped by three guiding values: authenticity, accountability, and creative problem-solving. She remains dedicated to building meaningful experiences that drive impact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-first-steps-a-nonlinear-college-journey&quot;&gt;The First Steps: A Nonlinear College Journey&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Britt Hall’s college experience wasn’t a straight path. In fact, it took nearly seven years to complete a bachelor’s degree. Initially pursuing music education and performance, Britt found themselves on an expected trajectory—until a single elective, “Storytelling and Puppetry,” reshaped their perspective. That class ignited a passion for storytelling, leading to a major shift into journalism and communications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Switching from a music program meant starting over, even taking a step back to community college before transferring again on a journalism scholarship. These experiences taught Britt valuable lessons in resilience, adaptability, and trusting one’s instincts—skills that would prove crucial in their career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-first-job-freelance-hustle-and-saying-yes&quot;&gt;The First Job: Freelance, Hustle, and Saying Yes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Britt’s first job after college wasn’t handed to them—it was built through experience and opportunity. While freelancing for the Corpus Christi Caller-Times, Britt wore many hats: general assignments reporter, copy editor, and even interim archivist. At the same time, they worked as a barista, eventually taking on training and marketing roles for the coffee shop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three months after graduation, Britt secured their first full-time role in marketing and communications for the Corpus Christi Symphony Orchestra—an opportunity that came from an earlier internship. The key lesson? Keep doors open, maintain good relationships, and recognize that every experience (even in retail and food service) builds skills that matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-career-built-on-passion-and-adaptability&quot;&gt;A Career Built on Passion and Adaptability&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to today, Britt leads a global team at Cisco, managing employee experience and enablement for hiring and internal talent movement programs. It’s a role that aligns almost perfectly with their Ikigai—the Japanese concept of purpose—combining passion, mission, vocation, and profession.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Britt’s journey from journalism to corporate leadership wasn’t accidental. It was guided by a mindset of embracing change, being willing to “figure it out,” and leveraging past experiences to build a unique and valuable career path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;advice-for-college-juniors-be-a-bricoleur&quot;&gt;Advice for College Juniors: Be a Bricoleur&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what advice does Britt have for students entering the workforce?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Say yes now, figure it out later.&lt;/strong&gt; Opportunities don’t always come neatly packaged. Trust yourself enough to take on challenges, even when you don’t feel fully prepared.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Build resilience.&lt;/strong&gt; The most adaptable and successful people share three traits: accepting reality, finding meaning in what they do, and improvising when necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Identify your values early.&lt;/strong&gt; Britt’s guiding principles—authenticity, accountability, and creative problem-solving—help in making decisions, setting boundaries, and maintaining work-life balance.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keep relationships strong.&lt;/strong&gt; The first full-time job came from an internship, and career growth often hinges on connections and a strong reputation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-takeaway-your-path-is-yours-to-make&quot;&gt;The Takeaway: Your Path is Yours to Make&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Britt Hall’s career isn’t one of rigid planning—it’s a testament to adaptability, lifelong learning, and saying “yes” to the right opportunities. For college juniors feeling uncertain, the message is clear: your path doesn’t have to be linear. Trust the journey, embrace change, and build a career that aligns with your passions and strengths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, as you plan your next steps, remember—you have the power to shape your own story, just like Britt Hall did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’d love to spot light you.  Tell us your story at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sujeeth.org/stories&quot;&gt;https://www.sujeeth.org/stories&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="spotlight" /><summary type="html">Britt Hall&apos;s adaptability, resilience, and strategic networking took her from journalism to corporate leadership. Discover practical tips for students on building experience, embracing change, and aligning their careers with their passions and strengths.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Adaptability: Marta Texidor’s Key</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Marta-Texidor/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Adaptability: Marta Texidor’s Key" /><published>2023-10-05T01:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-10-05T01:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Marta-Texidor</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Marta-Texidor/">&lt;p&gt;The Sujeeth Foundation Spotlight series shares stories of individuals who have successfully transitioned from academia to industry, aiming to inspire and educate college students on their own career journeys. In this spotlight, we introduce &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/martatexidor/&quot;&gt;Marta Texidor&lt;/a&gt;, a dedicated professional who has made a significant impact in the tech industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;meet-marta-texidor&quot;&gt;Meet Marta Texidor&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marta Texidor is currently the Director of Customer Success for Pharma and MedTech at Microsoft. Her career journey has been a remarkable one, driven by her passion for helping others achieve their goals and her unwavering commitment to personal growth. After initially interning as a software developer, she landed her first job as a software developer with Atos. Demonstrating her versatility, she later transitioned into a customer-facing role at Progress Software, honing her skills in customer relationships. Eventually, Marta found her calling at Microsoft, where she excelled as a Customer Success Manager, specializing in digital transformation within the Healthcare and Life Sciences sectors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-call-to-adventure-college-and-beyond&quot;&gt;The Call to Adventure: College and Beyond&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marta’s journey started like many college students, with a dream and a degree. She graduated with a degree in Computer Science engineering and a thirst for knowledge. Her first job while she was still at school was a unique one - she became a private Math tutor. While it may seem unrelated to her eventual career in the tech industry, this role challenged her to find creative ways to make complex concepts understandable. Each student had their unique learning style, and Marta’s adaptability helped her connect with them on a personal level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;alert alert-info&quot; role=&quot;alert&quot;&gt;
    &lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-info-circle&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;Note:&lt;/b&gt;
    Lesson 1: The Power of Adaptability - In a world that often values binary thinking, Marta learned to embrace the ambiguity and explore the grey areas. She discovered that there is beauty in the in-between, where creativity and innovation thrive.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;navigating-the-path-to-her-dream-job&quot;&gt;Navigating the Path to Her Dream Job&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marta’s journey into the tech industry began with a simple conversation and networking. In a pre-internet era, personal connections mattered most. Through a friend’s mother, she secured her first job as a Java Developer. While she lacked experience, Marta’s attitude set her apart. She embraced the opportunity to learn and welcomed feedback as a means to grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;alert alert-info&quot; role=&quot;alert&quot;&gt;
    &lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-info-circle&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;Note:&lt;/b&gt;
    Lesson 2: Networking and Attitude Matter - Sometimes, it’s not about your experience but your eagerness to learn and your openness to feedback that can pave the way to success.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;embracing-diversity-in-college&quot;&gt;Embracing Diversity in College&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marta’s college experience played a crucial role in shaping her career. She attended a college that exposed her to a diverse range of people and cultures. This experience opened her mind to the beauty of diversity and the commonalities that bind us all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In college, I realized we all have much more in common than we might think at first glance. Finding those connections points has now become one of my strengths, helping me grow in my career, partnering with others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;alert alert-info&quot; role=&quot;alert&quot;&gt;
    &lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-info-circle&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;Note:&lt;/b&gt;
    Lesson 3: Finding Strength in Diversity - Marta’s ability to find common ground with people from various backgrounds has become one of her strengths in her career. It has allowed her to connect with others, fostering a sense of belonging and creating meaningful partnerships.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;advice-for-aspiring-professionals&quot;&gt;Advice for Aspiring Professionals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marta leaves college students with a valuable piece of advice - there are no wrong turns, only unexpected paths. Your career journey may not follow a straight line, but what matters most is aligning your choices with your values. When you do that, everything else will fall into place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;My biggest shift in thinking, coming from an engineering background, was that not everything is 1s or 0s, black or white. There is beauty in the ambiguity and the grey areas. Because it is not as defined as the extremes, you can play and find your own path and framework to work with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion-your-journey-awaits&quot;&gt;Conclusion: Your Journey Awaits&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you embark on your academic and career journey, remember Marta’s story. Embrace adaptability, network, maintain a positive attitude, and celebrate diversity. The Sujeeth Foundation encourages you to find your unique path, just as Marta did, and to view education as a tool and to embrace concepts from books like “Grit,” “Work Out Loud,” and “Mindset” to guide your way. &lt;a href=&quot;https://portal.sujeeth.org/#whitepaper&quot;&gt;Download the whitepaper&lt;/a&gt; to learn more. Her story serves as an inspiration for all aspiring professionals, reminding them that their career paths may take unexpected turns, but with the right mindset and determination, they can achieve their goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’d love to spot light you.  Tell us your story at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sujeeth.org/stories&quot;&gt;https://www.sujeeth.org/stories&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="spotlight" /><summary type="html">Marta Texidor developed adaptability, networking, and a positive attitude to go from software developer to Director of Customer Success at Microsoft. Discover practical tips for students on embracing diversity, finding common ground, and navigating their career paths effectively.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Craft Your Narrative: Avi Sujeeth</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Avi-Sujeeth/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Craft Your Narrative: Avi Sujeeth" /><published>2023-09-14T01:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-09-14T01:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Avi-Sujeeth</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Avi-Sujeeth/">&lt;p&gt;The Sujeeth Foundation Spotlight highlights the stories of individuals who made the jump from academia to industry.  We share stories to inspire and educate.  We hope students can leverage this experience in their own journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Avi Sujeeth is a Director of the Sujeeth Foundation.  Avi worked for Microsoft for fifteen years in field sales roles like Customer Success Manager and Sales Engineer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Avi describes the underlying interest in his current job:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’m passionate about the ability of technology to drive transformational change. I think the need in education and healthcare is prescient. We have a shortage in teaching and clinician talent. In addition, we are challenged to deliver better outcomes. Graduates should do work they are passionate about. Patients should be able to increase their life span. I think technology can help education institutions advance in research, promote new ways of learning, and deliver experiences in an unmatched way. In addition, I think technology can help health care organizations increase clinician productivity, engage with patients in new ways, and revolutionize how population health is managed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Avi Sujeeth began his academic journey like many of you, as a college student. He attended Washington University and, like most students, had his sights set on a specific career path, aiming for consulting or investment banking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Avi graduated, he faced one of the most challenging job markets in recent history, marked by the fallout from the Lehman Brothers’ bankruptcy. He applied to countless companies, endured 30 interviews, and reached 10 final interviews before finally receiving one job offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Avi:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I think it was difficult because of the market situation and because I was trying to make a career transition - I was trying to get into strategic consulting or investment banking. I didn’t have a strong story around how my previous experiences had prepared me for those roles. In fact, when I did get a job it was with Microsoft sales. I was able to tell a story of how my financial experience, technology passion, and sales experience had prepared me to sell technology to finance departments in enterprises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;alert alert-info&quot; role=&quot;alert&quot;&gt;
    &lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-info-circle&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;Note:&lt;/b&gt;
    Lesson 1 - Building Your Narrative. Avi’s journey taught him the importance of crafting a compelling narrative about how his experiences had prepared him for a role. People hire you because they believe in your potential. Crafting a story that helps others understand your capabilities can make all the difference.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Avi started his career as a Modern Work Solution Specialist at Microsoft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It was a sales role positioning Microsoft’s investments in SharePoint with clients. I didn’t really understand sales when I was first hired. I thought in order to be successful, a sales person had to out position the competition by maintaining control. I learned that sometimes you can get more success when you follow instead of leading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As his career advanced he has had over seven roles with four significant job transformations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;As I’ve mapped out my career, one of the hardest activities was to develop a career plan. I haven’t a traditional track into management. Instead, I’ve focused on solving difficult problems as an individual contributor leader. As I’ve mastered skills, I’ve looked to move into adjacent roles to increase my impact. I’ve used frameworks like the next, next job to think about skills or relationships I need to develop in my current role.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;alert alert-info&quot; role=&quot;alert&quot;&gt;
    &lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-info-circle&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;Note:&lt;/b&gt;
    Lesson 2 - Adaptability is Key. College students tend to envision success as linear, but Avi’s career demonstrates that adaptability is a key ingredient in success. Don’t be afraid to pivot, learn new skills, and explore adjacent roles to maximize your impact.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Avi has published several blogs discussing his career path and how he aligns his career decisions with his core values:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/my-core-values-integrity-heart-avi-sujeeth?lipi=urn%3Ali%3Apage%3Ad_flagship3_profile_view_base%3BMTJlBbv8SqSlgG8%2Bj%2FyXhw%3D%3D&quot;&gt;My Core Values - Integrity and Heart&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/what-do-i-want-when-grow-up-avi-sujeeth?lipi=urn%3Ali%3Apage%3Ad_flagship3_profile_view_base%3BMTJlBbv8SqSlgG8%2Bj%2FyXhw%3D%3D&quot;&gt;What do I want to do when I grow up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/my-journey-patient-experience-avi-sujeeth?lipi=urn%3Ali%3Apage%3Ad_flagship3_profile_view_base%3BMTJlBbv8SqSlgG8%2Bj%2FyXhw%3D%3D&quot;&gt;My Journey to Patient Experience&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/find-your-passion-how-i-found-my-career-path-avi-sujeeth?lipi=urn%3Ali%3Apage%3Ad_flagship3_profile_view_base%3BMTJlBbv8SqSlgG8%2Bj%2FyXhw%3D%3D&quot;&gt;Find Your Passion: How I found my Career Path&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Avi shares:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’ve also spent time leveraging thinking about my core values and how they align to the career path I’m navigating. While I wouldn’t have predict my career path, it has been incredibly rewarding. I look forward to seeing how it continues to evolve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;alert alert-info&quot; role=&quot;alert&quot;&gt;
    &lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-info-circle&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;Note:&lt;/b&gt;
    Lesson 3 - Aligning with Core Values.  Throughout his journey, Avi has consistently aligned his career decisions with his core values. Understanding what truly matters to you can guide your career choices, making your journey more fulfilling and purpose-driven.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you embark on your academic and career journey, remember that you have agency. You can shape your path, navigate challenges, and find purpose in unexpected places. The Sujeeth Foundation encourages you to view education as a tool, just as Avi did, and to embrace concepts from books like “Grit,” “Work Out Loud,” and “Mindset” to guide your way.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://portal.sujeeth.org/#whitepaper&quot;&gt;Download the whitepaper&lt;/a&gt; to learn more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’d love to spot light you.  Tell us your story at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sujeeth.org/stories&quot;&gt;https://www.sujeeth.org/stories&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="spotlight" /><summary type="html">Avi Sujeeth&apos;s relied on perseverance, strategic storytelling, and adaptability to launch and grow his career. Discover practical tips for students on building a compelling narrative, embracing career pivots, and aligning career decisions with core values.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Work Out Loud Archives</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/career/Work-Out-Loud-Archives/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Work Out Loud Archives" /><published>2023-06-03T01:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-06-03T01:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/career/Work-Out-Loud-Archives</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/career/Work-Out-Loud-Archives/">&lt;p&gt;Working Out Loud is a concept coined by John Stepper.  In today’s interconnected and fast-paced world, success is not solely determined by individual brilliance or expertise; it thrives on collaboration, community, and the power of networks. Enter “Work Out Loud” (WOL), a transformative approach that empowers professionals to harness the full potential of collaboration, share their work openly, and cultivate meaningful connections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At its core, WOL is a mindset and practice that encourages individuals to make their work visible, actively contribute to the success of others, and build purposeful networks. It is a departure from traditional silos and closed-door practices, ushering in a new era of transparency, generosity, and collective growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this digital age, where information flows freely and barriers to communication have diminished, the power of working out loud has become more evident than ever. By sharing our ideas, progress, and challenges with a wider audience, we tap into the collective intelligence of our networks and unlock opportunities for collaboration, feedback, and learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, WOL is not just about broadcasting our work; it’s about building relationships that transcend geographical boundaries and professional hierarchies. It’s about finding like-minded individuals, diverse perspectives, and unexpected collaborations that fuel innovation and drive personal and organizational growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John even created a guide to help people facilitate their own work out loud circles.  I envision where a community will build around the Sujeeth Foundation and we will be able to connect applicants to each other as they strive to determine their passion and achieve their purpose.  To help with that community building I’ve gathered John’s guides in this blog post:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/wol/wol-circle-guides-v4.5-week-1.pdf&quot;&gt;Week 1: Attune your attention&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
In your first week, after getting to know your other Circle members a bit better, each of you will pick your own individual goal. Then you’ll take a step towards that goal by creating a “relationship list,” an initial list of people related to your goal.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/wol/wol-circle-guides-v4.5-week-2.pdf&quot;&gt;Week 2: Offer your first contributions&lt;/a&gt;
In Week 2, you’ll make simple contributions to people on your relationship list, deepening relationships in a small way. Just reviewing the list will further attune your attention to your goal, and the small steps you take each week will gradually increase your sense of empowerment.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/wol/wol-circle-guides-v4.5-week-3.pdf&quot;&gt;Week 3: Take three small steps&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
In Week 3, you’ll make a simple adjustment to managing your time, you’ll add to your relationship list, and you’ll offer another kind of contribution. These small steps will help reinforce and expand your practice.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/wol/wol-circle-guides-v4.5-week-4.pdf&quot;&gt;Week 4: Earn someone else’s attention&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
How you present your contribution can make all the difference. This week, you’ll practice refining the way you write your messages and how you approach people in general. These exercises will make your contributions feel more personal and valuable, and more likely to be effective.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/wol/wol-circle-guides-v4.5-week-5.pdf&quot;&gt;Week 5: Make it personal&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Most people think far too narrowly about what they have to offer. This week can change that for you. The exercises will help you understand how the broad set of things you may take for granted - what makes you you - can serve as the basis for meaningful connections with others.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/wol/wol-circle-guides-v4.5-week-6.pdf&quot;&gt;Week 6: Improve your visibility&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
It’s hard for anyone to discover you and your work when you’re invisible. This week, to improve your chances of making connections, you’ll take a step towards improving your online presence. Then you’ll use your improved presence to deepen a relationship.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/wol/wol-circle-guides-v4.5-week-7.pdf&quot;&gt;Week 7: Be purposeful&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
This week, you’ll do one of the most powerful exercises in your Circle: “A letter from your future self.” By articulating a longer-term vision of what might be possible, you‘ll increase the chances of that vision becoming a reality.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/wol/wol-circle-guides-v4.5-week-8.pdf&quot;&gt;Week 8: Make it a habit&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Although you’ve spent seven weeks thinking of your goal in terms of people and contributions, you’re still working on making it a habit and mindset. It’s natural, for example, to struggle with finding time to work your list or remembering to follow up. This week, you’ll explore ways to reinforce your new habit so it takes less effort and feels increasingly natural, and to overcome the inevitable challenges and setbacks. Then you’ll practice empathy (again) in a way that might surprise you - and will certainly distinguish you.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/wol/wol-circle-guides-v4.5-week-9.pdf&quot;&gt;Week 9: Explore more original contributions&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
At this point in your Circle, you’re ready to further expand your range of contributions by making more of your work and thinking visible. Even if this is new to some of you or makes you uncomfortable, the exercises this week will help you take a step, allowing you to create something simple that’s also generous and useful.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/wol/wol-circle-guides-v4.5-week-10.pdf&quot;&gt;Week 10: Become more systematic&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Having a system can make things easier. This week, you’ll work with two simple systems, one for identifying new contributions and one for managing your relationship list. Then you’ll offer something which you may never have thought of as a contribution.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/wol/wol-circle-guides-v4.5-week-11.pdf&quot;&gt;Week 11: Imagine the possibilities&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
So far, the focus has been on your individual contributions and connections. In Week 11, you’ll expand your sense of what’s possible by thinking more broadly about your network, your role in it, and what you might accomplish together.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/wol/wol-circle-guides-v4.5-week-12.pdf&quot;&gt;Week 12: Reflect and celebrate&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
This final week marks the end of a process, and maybe a kind of beginning. You’ll reflect on what has changed for you and what might
come. In your last exercise, you’ll make several additional contributions, including some for yourself. Hold this final meeting over lunch or dinner if you can - or come up with some other creative way to create an environment that’s conducive to celebration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="career" /><summary type="html">John Stepper&apos;s WOL guides, which provide a structured approach for individuals to implement the WOL practice. These guides span a twelve-week period and cover various aspects of building relationships, making contributions, refining communication, improving visibility, articulating a vision, developing habits, and expanding one&apos;s network.</summary></entry></feed>