<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-04-05T22:46:57-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">The Sujeeth Foundation</title><subtitle>Unlocking opportunity through education. The Sujeeth Foundation helps students network into their first job. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Career Circle Content</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/announcements/Career-Circle-Content/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Career Circle Content" /><published>2025-04-03T01:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-04-03T01:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/announcements/Career-Circle-Content</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/announcements/Career-Circle-Content/">&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Career Circle Program&lt;/strong&gt; incorporates a diverse set of content designed to help students explore their strengths, prepare for job opportunities, and build a strong professional presence. Below is a breakdown of the key content pieces, along with the guiding principle and reasons for its inclusion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;exercise-build-your-coat-of-arms&quot;&gt;Exercise: Build Your Coat of Arms&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
This exercise invites students to reflect on their personal and professional journey by mapping out their past (10 years ago), present (now), and future (5 years from now). The exercise encourages deep self-reflection and helps students understand how their experiences shape their career aspirations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Principle&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Self-awareness leads to clarity&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
By understanding where they’ve been and where they want to go, students can set a course for the future that aligns with their values and goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why Included&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
This exercise helps students gain clarity about their strengths and direction. It sets the foundation for a focused job search and helps them make decisions based on self-understanding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;video-dare-to-lead-brené-brown-interview&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sujeeth-my.sharepoint.com/:v:/g/personal/avisuj_sujeeth_org/EUfm1vSSIDpDoAR0FhAbRLEBhr4UkOhbG6PqvGnimILd3w?e=0VWnsJ&quot;&gt;Video: “Dare to Lead” Brené Brown Interview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
In this video, Brené Brown discusses the importance of vulnerability and courage in leadership. She emphasizes that showing vulnerability builds trust, an essential element in forming meaningful relationships and leading effectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Principle&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Vulnerability builds trust and connection&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
Leaders and professionals who are open, authentic, and vulnerable tend to build stronger relationships and are better at influencing others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why Included&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
This video inspires students to embrace vulnerability in their professional journey, encouraging them to be authentic and trust-building in their job search and career development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;video-how-to-find-your-purpose&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sujeeth-my.sharepoint.com/:v:/g/personal/avisuj_sujeeth_org/EaAeQPGvktZOotqjdHqKQXEBFnN5TQl9srDrOwk7rCZoiw?e=fqrSzB&quot;&gt;Video: How to Find Your Purpose&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
This video guides students through the process of identifying their purpose by focusing on passions, skills, and values. It encourages them to connect their personal interests with their professional goals to find a fulfilling career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Principle&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Purpose fuels motivation and direction&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
Understanding one’s purpose is key to finding career satisfaction and achieving long-term success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why Included&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
Helping students discover their purpose ensures they pursue careers that align with their personal values and passions, resulting in more fulfilling work and sustained motivation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;exercise-brainstorm-career-path-with-chatgpt&quot;&gt;Exercise: Brainstorm Career Path with ChatGPT&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
In this exercise, students use ChatGPT to brainstorm potential career paths based on their interests, skills, and experiences. The tool helps students identify new opportunities and guide them in mapping out a clear career trajectory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Principle&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Exploration leads to informed decision-making&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
By exploring various options, students gain insights into possible career paths they may not have considered otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why Included&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
This exercise empowers students to think broadly about their career options and helps them identify paths that align with their aspirations, increasing the likelihood of long-term success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;video-connect-with-hiring-managers&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sujeeth-my.sharepoint.com/:v:/g/personal/avisuj_sujeeth_org/EbxhQj4K-7VDoYk4Xvnv9q4B84lhssH67jQtYXOPDVm03Q?e=UfiJQ8&quot;&gt;Video: Connect with Hiring Managers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
This video offers practical tips on how to network and connect directly with hiring managers. It emphasizes the importance of reaching out, building rapport, and engaging in meaningful conversations to create opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Principle&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Networking is about building relationships, not just seeking opportunities&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
Building authentic connections with hiring managers can open doors and help students stand out in the job market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why Included&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
The ability to connect with hiring managers is a valuable skill in a competitive job market. This content helps students understand how to approach these professionals and build lasting relationships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;video-the-origin-of-why&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sujeeth-my.sharepoint.com/:v:/g/personal/avisuj_sujeeth_org/EfIkLI930CZAl6KZYh1iWpEBCcQtnM96m0UvisgRor92AQ?e=nHVGUQ&quot;&gt;Video: The Origin of Why&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
This video discusses Simon Sinek’s “Start with Why” framework, explaining the importance of understanding your core beliefs and values as a leader or professional. It highlights how knowing your “why” provides direction and drives meaningful action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Principle&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Clarity of purpose guides actions&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
When students understand their “why,” they can make decisions that align with their core values and goals, leading to more authentic career paths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why Included&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
This video helps students identify their core purpose, which is crucial for personal and professional alignment. It also serves as a foundation for crafting meaningful resumes and LinkedIn profiles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;video-build-a-strong-base-resume&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sujeeth-my.sharepoint.com/:v:/g/personal/avisuj_sujeeth_org/EXkFm9OMccRDma51Yus1k5wBWQipaBE3V2GpEqAcHT6nzQ?e=G1r55a&quot;&gt;Video: Build a Strong Base Resume&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
This video teaches students how to create a strong base resume, focusing on essential elements like formatting, highlighting achievements, and tailoring the document to specific roles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Principle&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Preparation is key to presenting yourself effectively&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
A strong, well-crafted resume is the first step in catching a recruiter’s attention and landing interviews.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why Included&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
A resume is the cornerstone of a job application. This content helps students present themselves professionally and ensures their resume is aligned with industry expectations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;video-build-a-linkedin-profile&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sujeeth-my.sharepoint.com/:v:/g/personal/avisuj_sujeeth_org/ETnPQnZv0_pDnJwvBLoeZPABCMQWEDeQ_y4eWpAYxfjd8A?e=7EEuAI&quot;&gt;Video: Build a LinkedIn Profile&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
In this video, students learn how to optimize their LinkedIn profile to enhance their professional presence online. The video covers profile optimization, the importance of a professional headline, and how to use LinkedIn for networking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Principle&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Your online presence matters&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
An optimized LinkedIn profile is a powerful tool for job seekers to connect with professionals, showcase their skills, and build credibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why Included&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
As a vital component of any job search, a strong LinkedIn profile helps students network, connect with recruiters, and showcase their experience in an easily accessible way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;video-working-out-loud-with-john-stepper&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sujeeth-my.sharepoint.com/:v:/g/personal/avisuj_sujeeth_org/Ecg8Ca6JT6xCn7EBVQcWgZkB060-0k8_IQ3iXHy5fos6ZQ?e=SuJGau&quot;&gt;Video: Working Out Loud with John Stepper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
John Stepper’s concept of “Working Out Loud” encourages professionals to share their work openly and help others achieve their goals. It’s a practice that builds relationships and increases visibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Principle&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Transparency builds trust and relationships&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
By openly sharing progress and offering support to others, students can build their network and demonstrate thought leadership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why Included&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
“Working Out Loud” encourages students to engage with their professional community by contributing and sharing, fostering strong relationships that can aid in career growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;video-10-ways-to-contribute&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sujeeth-my.sharepoint.com/:v:/g/personal/avisuj_sujeeth_org/EXt0nsgX_rtInef8QMeKw6IB_xnaNKVzoqWUlt49Jt8uIg?e=N23zVK&quot;&gt;Video: 10 Ways to Contribute&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
This video outlines practical ways students can contribute to their professional community. It encourages students to share knowledge, offer support, and engage in activities that build their personal brand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Principle&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Contributing adds value to both you and others&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
The act of contributing not only helps others but also strengthens the student’s professional profile and reputation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why Included&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
Contributing to the community is an effective way to grow one’s network and establish a professional reputation. This video empowers students to actively engage and provide value in their networks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;exercise-chatgpt-follow-leaders&quot;&gt;Exercise: ChatGPT Follow Leaders&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
This exercise encourages students to identify thought leaders in their field using ChatGPT. By researching and engaging with these leaders, students can expand their network and gain valuable insights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Principle&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Engagement with thought leaders enhances learning and networking&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
Connecting with industry leaders and influencers provides students with insights and opens doors for new opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why Included&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
This exercise helps students identify individuals who can support their professional development and guides them in establishing connections that may be crucial for their career growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;video-branding-yourself-through-social-media&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sujeeth-my.sharepoint.com/:v:/g/personal/avisuj_sujeeth_org/ERtkUAYJb91Dopbdbn027PQBvni8XLmgd1anFdQe18jIjg?e=uoLLqa&quot;&gt;Video: Branding Yourself Through Social Media&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
This video emphasizes the importance of managing one’s social media presence to build a professional brand. It covers strategies for showcasing expertise, engaging with others, and maintaining a consistent image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Principle&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Your personal brand shapes how others perceive you&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
Social media is an extension of your professional identity, and managing it carefully helps students build credibility and influence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why Included&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
In today’s digital world, a strong social media brand is essential for networking and job searching. This video teaches students how to use social media to support their professional goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;video-how-many-jobs-should-i-apply-to&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sujeeth-my.sharepoint.com/:v:/g/personal/avisuj_sujeeth_org/ESCvA495XB1HtUZhZyQq7RcBlFRVAXW30NLdLmQ1vAZ0pw?e=mxeicv&quot;&gt;Video: How Many Jobs Should I Apply To?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
This video explores the balance between applying to many jobs versus focusing on quality opportunities. It offers guidance on how to streamline the job application process and avoid burnout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Principle&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Quality over quantity in job applications&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
A focused approach is more effective than applying indiscriminately. Tailoring applications ensures better chances of success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why Included&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
This content helps students avoid the trap of applying to too many jobs without a strategy, encouraging them to focus their efforts on high-quality opportunities that align with their goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;video-storytelling-during-the-interview&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sujeeth-my.sharepoint.com/:v:/g/personal/avisuj_sujeeth_org/ETCiD619oDNEtHwRRGXIOD4B1rMmRfvIqLWBE8m13uCjhA?e=kumZ8i&quot;&gt;Video: Storytelling During the Interview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
In this video, students learn the importance of storytelling in interviews. The STAR (Situation, Task, Action, Result) method is introduced to help students structure their responses effectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Principle&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Storytelling builds a compelling narrative&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
Effective storytelling makes students’ experiences more memorable and helps interviewers see how their skills and values align with the role.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why Included&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
Storytelling is a key skill in interviews. This video teaches students how to craft compelling stories that demonstrate their capabilities and make a lasting impression on interviewers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;video-the-lean-startup-book-summary&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sujeeth-my.sharepoint.com/:v:/g/personal/avisuj_sujeeth_org/ESQa5aWTv8RLmVAF0dLqpIQBiNhCSas-vo-uOCH_djQuKQ?e=u2pdhv&quot;&gt;Video: The Lean Startup Book Summary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
This video introduces the principles of the Lean Startup methodology, focusing on how to experiment, learn from failures, and pivot to improve one’s approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Principle&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Failure is part of the process, and learning is continuous&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
The Lean Startup methodology encourages experimentation and iterative learning, which are essential for improving one’s job search approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why Included&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
This content helps students understand the value of failure as a learning opportunity, reinforcing the idea of constant iteration and improvement in their job search and career development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;video-ultimate-guide-to-following-up&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sujeeth-my.sharepoint.com/:v:/g/personal/avisuj_sujeeth_org/Efh0hQMuF3hOkZV_9GC4JIoB2NR7Q9nDTn4CXesL1YjkTQ?e=9As261&quot;&gt;Video: Ultimate Guide to Following Up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
This video teaches students the importance of following up after interviews. It provides practical tips on how to craft follow-up messages that leave a positive impression and reinforce a student’s interest in the role.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Principle&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Follow-up demonstrates professionalism and persistence&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
Effective follow-up can make the difference between getting the job or being overlooked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why Included&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
Following up is often overlooked but crucial for making a lasting impression. This content teaches students how to stay top of mind after an interview and improve their chances of success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;video-daniel-pink-on-the-power-of-regret&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sujeeth-my.sharepoint.com/:v:/g/personal/avisuj_sujeeth_org/EUQ5DUa2r4ZLrbAasT3G0KYBHqe9bdpg0vP40G6la9u2vA?e=YHsDJY&quot;&gt;Video: Daniel Pink on the Power of Regret&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
Daniel Pink explores the concept of regret and how it shapes decisions. He explains the four types of regret: foundation, boldness, moral, and connection, and how reflecting on them can guide future choices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Principle&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Regret provides valuable lessons for decision-making&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
By acknowledging and understanding regret, students can make more informed, aligned decisions in their careers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why Included&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
This video helps students reflect on their past decisions and use those insights to make better, more informed choices in their future careers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By engaging with this content, students are equipped with the tools, insights, and strategies they need to succeed in their job search and long-term career development. Each piece is designed to empower students, enhance their skills, and build a strong foundation for future success.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="announcements" /><summary type="html">Explore the Sujeeth Foundation&apos;s Career Circle Program, featuring a diverse set of content designed to help students build a strong professional presence. Learn about self-assessment exercises, resume building, networking strategies, job application tips, and interview preparation. Empower your career journey with our comprehensive guide.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Career Circle Volunteer FAQ</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/announcements/Career-Circle-Volunteer-FAQ/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Career Circle Volunteer FAQ" /><published>2025-04-03T01:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-04-03T01:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/announcements/Career-Circle-Volunteer-FAQ</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/announcements/Career-Circle-Volunteer-FAQ/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;general-program-info&quot;&gt;General Program Info&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;q-what-is-the-career-circle-program&quot;&gt;Q: What is the Career Circle Program?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A: It’s a 6-week virtual program that helps students grow personally and professionally by developing job search skills. Each week, students engage in guided group discussions, videos, and exercises focused on topics like resumes, interviews, networking, and negotiations.  To learn more check out the Facilitator Guide:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;q-who-is-the-program-for&quot;&gt;Q: Who is the program for?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A: Students, especially those starting to explore internships or their first full-time job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;q-what-happens-each-week&quot;&gt;Q: What happens each week?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A: Each session lasts one hour and includes group discussions, reflection exercises, videos, and practical skills. Each week focuses on a different theme, like self-assessment, job applications, and follow-up strategies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;working-with-students&quot;&gt;Working with Students&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;q-who-are-the-students&quot;&gt;Q: Who are the students?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A: These are college students. They are seeking support, guidance, and mentorship to help them navigate their career journeys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;q-can-i-reach-out-to-students-outside-of-the-sessions&quot;&gt;Q: Can I reach out to students outside of the sessions?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A: We encourage mentors to connect with students on LinkedIn or through the program’s group discussions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;q-do-i-need-to-impress-the-students&quot;&gt;Q: Do I need to impress the students?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A: Not at all. It’s about creating a supportive and learning-focused environment. The goal is to be genuine, share your experiences, and help them with their career development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;session-logistics&quot;&gt;Session Logistics&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;q-how-do-i-join-the-sessions&quot;&gt;Q: How do I join the sessions?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A: After signing up, you’ll receive Teams links and calendar invites for each session. Make sure to show up on time and engage in the discussions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;q-what-if-i-miss-a-session&quot;&gt;Q: What if I miss a session?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A: It’s important to attend as much as possible. If you miss a session, try to catch up with the group discussions or reach out to the program facilitators for updates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;q-do-i-need-to-prepare-anything-before-the-sessions&quot;&gt;Q: Do I need to prepare anything before the sessions?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A: Yes! Each week, we’ll provide a list of materials to review before the session, such as videos or reflection questions. This helps you contribute more effectively to the discussion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;during-the-sessions&quot;&gt;During the Sessions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;q-how-can-i-best-support-the-students&quot;&gt;Q: How can I best support the students?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A: Encourage open communication, share personal stories, and provide constructive feedback. Be empathetic to their challenges and create a comfortable space for them to ask questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;q-what-should-i-do-if-a-student-seems-unsure-or-nervous&quot;&gt;Q: What should I do if a student seems unsure or nervous?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A: Be patient and understanding. It’s normal for students to feel nervous in new environments. Offer reassurance and encourage them to share their thoughts when they feel ready.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;q-will-i-be-expected-to-grade-or-evaluate-the-students&quot;&gt;Q: Will I be expected to grade or evaluate the students?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A: No, you won’t grade or formally evaluate students. Your role is to offer mentorship and guidance, sharing feedback and insights based on your experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;making-the-most-of-the-program&quot;&gt;Making the Most of the Program&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;q-how-can-i-make-the-most-of-this-mentorship-experience&quot;&gt;Q: How can I make the most of this mentorship experience?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A: Engage in the discussions, share relevant experiences, ask questions that prompt critical thinking, and be available for follow-up outside the sessions if needed. Mentorship is about creating a lasting impact, even if it’s just one small piece of advice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;q-how-do-i-ensure-that-the-students-feel-supported-throughout-the-program&quot;&gt;Q: How do I ensure that the students feel supported throughout the program?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A: Be consistent and available. Check in with students outside the sessions, offer encouragement, and help them set actionable goals. Show them that you care about their growth, not just the program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;still-have-questions&quot;&gt;Still Have Questions?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to reach out to the program facilitators if you have any questions. We’re here to support you in making the most of your mentoring experience.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="announcements" /><summary type="html">Find detailed answers to common questions about the Sujeeth Foundation&apos;s Career Circle Program for mentors. Learn about the program&apos;s structure, including weekly themes like self-assessment, resume building, and networking. Understand how to engage with students, the logistics of joining sessions, and how to best support students through open communication and constructive feedback. Discover tips on preparing for sessions, building relationships, and making the most of your mentorship experience.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Career Circle Student FAQ</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/announcements/Career-Circle-Student-FAQ/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Career Circle Student FAQ" /><published>2025-04-03T01:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-04-03T01:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/announcements/Career-Circle-Student-FAQ</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/announcements/Career-Circle-Student-FAQ/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;general-program-info&quot;&gt;General Program Info&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;q-what-is-the-career-circle-program&quot;&gt;Q: What is the Career Circle Program?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A: It’s a 6-week virtual program designed to help you grow personally and professionally. Each week, you’ll focus on a different part of the job search process, such as self-assessment, resume building, interviewing, networking, and follow-up strategies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;q-who-is-the-program-for&quot;&gt;Q: Who is the program for?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A: The program is for college students, particularly those exploring internships or their first full-time job. It’s ideal for students who want support in navigating the job market and building their career confidence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;q-what-happens-each-week&quot;&gt;Q: What happens each week?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A: Each session is one hour long and includes group discussions, videos, reflection exercises, and practical skills development. Every week focuses on a different theme that builds upon the last, from self-assessment to negotiations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;working-with-volunteers&quot;&gt;Working with Volunteers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;q-who-are-the-volunteers&quot;&gt;Q: Who are the volunteers?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A: Volunteers are experienced professionals who are about 10 years into their careers. They are here to share advice, provide feedback, and help guide you through the program. They want to see you succeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;q-can-i-reach-out-to-volunteers-outside-of-the-sessions&quot;&gt;Q: Can I reach out to volunteers outside of the sessions?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A: Yes! You can connect with volunteers on LinkedIn. Be professional and respectful in your communication, and don’t hesitate to ask for advice or insights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;q-do-i-need-to-impress-the-volunteers&quot;&gt;Q: Do I need to impress the volunteers?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A: No need to impress anyone! The volunteers are here to support you and share their experiences. Be yourself, ask questions, and engage in the discussions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;session-logistics&quot;&gt;Session Logistics&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;q-how-do-i-join-the-sessions&quot;&gt;Q: How do I join the sessions?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A: After signing up, you’ll receive Teams links and calendar invites for each session. Show up on time and participate actively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;q-what-if-i-miss-a-session&quot;&gt;Q: What if I miss a session?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A: If you miss a session, it’s okay! Just catch up on the content in your own time and stay active in the LinkedIn group for updates and discussions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;q-do-i-need-to-prepare-anything-before-the-sessions&quot;&gt;Q: Do I need to prepare anything before the sessions?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A: Each week, we’ll share content, such as videos or reading materials, that will help you engage in the session. Prepare by reviewing this content and reflecting on the discussion questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;during-the-sessions&quot;&gt;During the Sessions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;q-what-if-im-nervous-to-talk-or-ask-questions&quot;&gt;Q: What if I’m nervous to talk or ask questions?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A: It’s totally normal to feel nervous! Just listen, and when you’re ready, share your thoughts or ask questions. Everyone is here to learn and support each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;q-what-kinds-of-things-should-i-share&quot;&gt;Q: What kinds of things should I share?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A: Share your thoughts on the weekly topics, ask about things you’re curious about, and be open to feedback. The more you share, the more you’ll get out of the program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;q-will-i-get-feedback&quot;&gt;Q: Will I get feedback?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A: Yes! You’ll receive feedback from both volunteers and peers. This feedback will help you improve your job search strategies and grow your professional skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;making-the-most-of-the-program&quot;&gt;Making the Most of the Program&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;q-what-should-i-focus-on-each-week&quot;&gt;Q: What should I focus on each week?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A: Engage in the discussions, ask questions, reflect on the content, and set goals for the next steps in your career development. Each week is designed to help you build on your skills progressively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;q-how-can-i-build-my-network-during-the-program&quot;&gt;Q: How can I build my network during the program?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A: Connect with peers and mentors on LinkedIn, post updates or questions, and comment on others’ posts. Networking is all about building authentic relationships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;q-will-this-help-me-get-a-job&quot;&gt;Q: Will this help me get a job?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A: The program will give you the skills, confidence, and network to increase your chances of success in the job market. While we can’t guarantee a job, the tools you’ll learn here are essential for job search success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;q-do-i-get-anything-for-completing-the-program&quot;&gt;Q: Do I get anything for completing the program?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A: Yes! You’ll receive a certificate of completion and a free copy of books behind the program. Most importantly, you’ll have gained valuable insights to boost your job search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;still-have-questions&quot;&gt;Still Have Questions?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any further questions, don’t hesitate to reach out to your mentor or connect with the program facilitators. We’re here to support your success!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="announcements" /><summary type="html">Find answers to common questions about the Sujeeth Foundation&apos;s Career Circle Program for college students. Learn about the program&apos;s structure, weekly activities, mentor-student interactions, and how to make the most of your mentorship experience.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Career Circle Guide</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/announcements/Career-Circle-Guide/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Career Circle Guide" /><published>2025-04-03T01:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-04-03T01:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/announcements/Career-Circle-Guide</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/announcements/Career-Circle-Guide/">&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Career Circle Program&lt;/strong&gt; is a 6-week mentorship program designed to help college juniors navigate the job search process. Each week focuses on a specific aspect of career development, offering students the tools and strategies they need to succeed in landing their first job. Mentors provide guidance, share personal experiences, and help students grow both personally and professionally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s an overview of the program week by week (&lt;a href=&quot;https://sujeeth-my.sharepoint.com/:p:/g/personal/avisuj_sujeeth_org/EZ84TmTmxwJMuKYm91IDq4YBFCmjL6MPoCSB1OndvbdDWQ?e=81DUEf&quot;&gt;Download Now&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;week-1-self-assessment-presentation&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sway.cloud.microsoft/kepypoEuftS0WnYy&quot;&gt;Week 1: Self-Assessment Presentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Objective&lt;/strong&gt;: Understand your strengths, goals, and areas of growth to make better career decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Agenda&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introductions and Icebreaker&lt;/strong&gt;: Get to know your peers and mentors.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brené Brown Interview Clip&lt;/strong&gt;: Discuss vulnerability and building trust in professional settings.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exercise - Build Your Coat of Arms&lt;/strong&gt;: Reflect on your personal and professional journey.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Group Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;: Focus on vulnerability, personal stories, and trust-building.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Week 1, the goal is to build trust within the group and encourage students to share their experiences. The content focuses on helping students craft a personal narrative that connects their goals with their past, addressing the common challenge of poorly differentiated resumes due to a lack of work history. To foster an emotionally safe environment for open sharing, the concept of vulnerability, based on Brené Brown’s work, is introduced. This allows students to feel comfortable expressing themselves authentically. Facilitators should model vulnerability, encourage reflection, create a non-judgmental space for sharing, and follow up to reinforce the power of vulnerability in professional growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;week-2-research--exploration-presentation&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sway.cloud.microsoft/PzxsrWjSmfNb90nx&quot;&gt;Week 2: Research &amp;amp; Exploration Presentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Objective&lt;/strong&gt;: Learn how to explore industries, roles, and companies that align with your goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Agenda&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Group Reflection&lt;/strong&gt;: Discuss strategies for exploring job opportunities.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video: Identifying Your Career Path&lt;/strong&gt;: Understanding your values and aligning them with career choices.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exercise&lt;/strong&gt;: Research companies and roles to identify your fit.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Group Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;: Share insights and challenges in the exploration process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Week 2, the goal is to help students understand that their target job should align with their individual interests, creating a unique fit they can explain in conversations and later use in crafting their resume. The concept of Ikigai is introduced, which helps define personal purpose by exploring the intersection of what you love, what you’re good at, what you can be paid for, and what the world needs. This allows students to reflect on their passions and skills to better target career opportunities. To further support this, a ChatGPT exercise is incorporated to encourage exploration. Additionally, networking is introduced through a LinkedIn Learning video focused on connecting with hiring managers. This prepares students to identify and engage with key individuals who can help them access job opportunities, once they have clarity on their target role.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;week-3-resume--preparation-presentation&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sway.cloud.microsoft/DRldmn7xluDQAvW9&quot;&gt;Week 3: Resume &amp;amp; Preparation Presentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Objective&lt;/strong&gt;: Develop a strong base resume and optimize your LinkedIn profile for job applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Agenda&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Group Reflection&lt;/strong&gt;: Discuss resume tailoring and challenges faced.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video: Building a Strong Base Resume&lt;/strong&gt;: Learn best practices for crafting a resume.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exercise: Create or Update LinkedIn Profile&lt;/strong&gt;: Align your online presence with your resume.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Group Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;: Share tips and strategies for a standout resume and profile.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Week 3, the goal is to guide students in personalizing their resumes to better match their target positions. To demonstrate the power of personalization, we introduce Simon Sinek’s interview, The Origin of Why, emphasizing that employers hire based on what they believe a candidate can contribute. Personalizing a resume helps clarify why a candidate is the right fit, making it more likely that a hiring manager will recognize the candidate’s potential. We also introduce the concept of a Base Resume, a tool that makes creating personalized resumes easier by keeping a comprehensive record of all experiences. This approach allows students to quickly tailor their resume to specific job roles instead of starting from scratch every time. The week concludes with a review of the basics for customizing LinkedIn profiles, ensuring that students understand how to present themselves effectively online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;week-4-networking-presentation&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sway.cloud.microsoft/qMBoyrKw83qTLRJd&quot;&gt;Week 4: Networking Presentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Objective&lt;/strong&gt;: Build a professional network through genuine relationships and effective strategies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Agenda&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Group Reflection&lt;/strong&gt;: Discuss the challenges and strategies for networking.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video: Working Out Loud&lt;/strong&gt;: Learn to build meaningful relationships by helping others.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exercise: ChatGPT Follow Leaders&lt;/strong&gt;: Identify key thought leaders to connect with.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Group Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;: Share experiences and strategies for successful networking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Week 4, the goal is to encourage students to start networking actively. We introduce John Stepper’s concept of Work Out Loud as a powerful foundation for building professional relationships. By sharing their work and progress openly, students can attract opportunities and connections that align with their goals. To facilitate this, we include a ChatGPT exercise designed to identify potential thought leaders and professionals who can help students network into target companies. The week wraps up with a review of social media best practices, equipping students with the knowledge they need to manage their online presence effectively for professional networking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;week-5-job-applications--interviews-presentation&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sway.cloud.microsoft/od5AapRHCqI8nAyO&quot;&gt;Week 5: Job Applications &amp;amp; Interviews Presentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Objective&lt;/strong&gt;: Refine your job search strategy and improve interview storytelling techniques.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Agenda&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Group Reflection&lt;/strong&gt;: Discuss job application strategies and the importance of “Start with Why”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video: How Many Jobs Should I Apply to?&lt;/strong&gt;: Explore the balance between quantity and quality in job applications.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exercise: Storytelling During Interviews&lt;/strong&gt;: Learn how to effectively communicate your experiences.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Group Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;: Share interview tips and challenges faced.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Week 5, the focus shifts to best practices for job applications and interviews. Students are encouraged to reflect on whether they should personalize each job application or take a mass application approach, a concept explored in the “How Many Jobs” podcast. The session also includes practice with the Situation, Task, Action, Result (STAR) framework, helping students craft compelling stories to communicate their experiences and outcomes effectively during interviews. Additionally, the Lean Startup approach is introduced, encouraging students to view each job application and interview as an experiment. This mindset promotes learning from each experience, improving their strategies over time and enhancing their chances of success in future job opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;week-6-follow-up--negotiation-presentation&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sway.cloud.microsoft/fDfKmMJai2dnuwDb&quot;&gt;Week 6: Follow-up &amp;amp; Negotiation Presentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Objective&lt;/strong&gt;: Master the art of following up after interviews and learn negotiation strategies for job offers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Agenda&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Group Reflection&lt;/strong&gt;: Discuss follow-up strategies and how they influence decision-making.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video: Ultimate Guide to Following Up&lt;/strong&gt;: Learn best practices for following up after interviews.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video: The Power of Regret by Daniel Pink&lt;/strong&gt;: Explore how regret can influence decisions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Group Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;: Reflect on follow-up challenges and strategies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Week 6, the focus is on cultivating authentic relationships for long-term career success. Rather than treating networking and follow-ups as transactional, students are encouraged to prioritize meaningful connections. The session introduces The Power of Regret by Daniel Pink, which explores four types of regret—foundation, boldness, moral, and connection—and how they shape decision-making. By reflecting on relationship regrets, students can make more intentional choices in their professional interactions. While job searches often aim to avoid mistakes, setbacks and regrets can serve as valuable learning opportunities, guiding students toward better decisions and stronger professional relationships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our goal is to help students network into their first job.  By catching them where they are, we can coach them on subjects that matter to their individual journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best mentors:
1️⃣Facilitate discussion instead of presenting content
2️⃣Respond to requests instead of staying locked in the agenda
3️⃣Explain the principle instead of focusing on specifics&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Career Circle Program offers a comprehensive framework for students to develop the skills and mindset necessary for success in their job search. Throughout each week, students will gain hands-on experience and valuable insights to help them navigate the complexities of entering the workforce.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="announcements" /><summary type="html">Explore the Sujeeth Foundation&apos;s Career Circle Guide, detailing a 6-week mentorship program for college juniors. Learn about weekly activities, self-assessment, research, resume building, networking, job applications, and interview preparation. Gain insights to navigate the job search process effectively.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Stepping Stones: Will Kyle</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Will-Kyle/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Stepping Stones: Will Kyle" /><published>2025-03-06T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2025-03-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Will-Kyle</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Will-Kyle/">&lt;p&gt;The Sujeeth Foundation Spotlight highlights the stories of individuals who made the jump from academia to industry.  We share stories to inspire and educate.  We hope students can leverage this experience in their own journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Navigating a career path can be daunting for college juniors looking ahead to life after graduation. With uncertainty, competition, and the challenge of finding the right fit, it’s easy to feel overwhelmed. But stories of success can inspire and guide us—and Will Kyle’s journey from an entry-level sales job to leading a team at Amazon Web Services (AWS) is one of perseverance, adaptability, and growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#Starting Out: The First Job That Built a Foundation
Will Kyle’s first job out of college was far from glamorous—selling steel buildings. It wasn’t his dream job, nor was it in an industry he was particularly passionate about, but it was an opportunity to gain experience, develop his skills, and prove himself in the professional world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time, the economy was in a recession, making job opportunities scarce. Will applied to any and every sales role he could find. After spotting an ad online for a steel building company, he took the leap. His role involved managing a network of steel building dealers, prospecting new customers, and running advertising campaigns. The company was resistant to technology, forcing him to work without the efficiencies of modern tools. Yet, instead of seeing this as a setback, he saw it as a learning experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With no structured training in sales, Will took ownership of his own professional development. He read books, sought mentorship, and pushed himself out of his comfort zone. The key lesson? Success is rarely handed to you—it’s something you must actively pursue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;climbing-the-ladder-wills-career-at-amazon-and-aws&quot;&gt;Climbing the Ladder: Will’s Career at Amazon and AWS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will’s persistence and commitment to learning paved the way for his entry into major corporate roles. He spent have spent 12 years at Amazon, 8 years in ecommerce and 4 years at AWS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, as an Enterprise Sales Leader at AWS, Will is responsible for business planning, consultative selling, and leading high-impact initiatives. Over the past four years at AWS, he has excelled in multiple roles, including Senior Account Executive, where he leveraged his deep expertise in sales presentations and strategic client engagement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His career at AWS has given him the opportunity to lead a team of professionals, drive enterprise growth, and work at the cutting edge of cloud technology. Most importantly, he has continued to develop his passion for mentorship—helping individuals advance their careers both within and outside of Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lessons-from-the-journey-building-a-network-and-asking-for-help&quot;&gt;Lessons from the Journey: Building a Network and Asking for Help&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reflecting on his career, Will emphasizes the importance of networking and mentorship. “Every single person you meet is an opportunity to expand your network. Never burn a bridge,” he advises. Throughout his career, he has found that there are always people willing to help—but it’s up to you to ask for guidance. Taking initiative in building relationships and seeking mentorship can be game-changing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;advice-for-college-juniors-the-first-job-is-just-a-stepping-stone&quot;&gt;Advice for College Juniors: The First Job is Just a Stepping Stone&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For college juniors about to embark on their professional journeys, Will offers one crucial piece of advice: Be patient and focus on building experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your first job out of school doesn’t have to be your dream job. It’s a stepping stone—a chance to learn, build skills, and prove yourself to future employers. Instead of limiting yourself to roles that seem perfect, embrace opportunities that allow you to grow. Your passions and goals will evolve over time, and the most important thing is to keep moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will Kyle’s career path is a testament to the power of resilience, continuous learning, and strategic networking. Whether you’re a college junior trying to find direction or an early-career professional seeking motivation, his story serves as a reminder that every experience—no matter how small—can be a building block for future success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay open to opportunities, invest in relationships, and never stop learning. Your journey is just beginning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’d love to spot light you.  Tell us your story at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sujeeth.org/stories&quot;&gt;https://www.sujeeth.org/stories&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="spotlight" /><summary type="html">Explore the inspiring career journey of Will Kyle, from selling steel buildings to becoming an Enterprise Sales Leader at AWS. Learn how perseverance, mentorship, and strategic networking helped him navigate challenges and achieve success. Discover practical tips for students on building experience, embracing opportunities, and making the most of their first job.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Find Your Why: Valerie Bergman</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Valerie-Bergman/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Find Your Why: Valerie Bergman" /><published>2025-03-06T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2025-03-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Valerie-Bergman</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Valerie-Bergman/">&lt;p&gt;The Sujeeth Foundation Spotlight highlights the stories of individuals who made the jump from academia to industry.  We share stories to inspire and educate.  We hope students can leverage this experience in their own journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As students begin to navigate the bridge between academics and career aspirations, it can feel like an overwhelming journey. Questions about the right first job, long-term goals, and personal fulfillment often weigh heavily on students. That’s why we’re thrilled to spotlight &lt;strong&gt;Valerie Bergman&lt;/strong&gt;, a Field Sales Specialist for Data and AI in Azure at Microsoft, whose career journey offers both inspiration and practical advice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Valerie Bergman’s career spans over 20 years, from starting as a software engineer to becoming a Data &amp;amp; AI Specialist at Microsoft. Along the way, she led IT strategy at Avtex Solutions, guided enterprise customers as a technology strategist, and now helps businesses innovate with AI and data solutions. Her journey reflects a focus on solving problems, driving innovation, and mentoring future STEM leaders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;aligning-passion-with-profession&quot;&gt;Aligning Passion with Profession&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Valerie’s current role at Microsoft combines her technical expertise with her passion for helping others. She thrives on solving complex problems and helping her customers justify their investments in innovation. Her journey exemplifies the Japanese concept of &lt;strong&gt;Ikigai&lt;/strong&gt;, or “reason for being,” as she’s managed to align her passion, mission, vocation, and profession.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Valerie’s story is a testament to the importance of finding work that resonates deeply with your skills and values. She believes that career success isn’t just about the “how” but about understanding the “&lt;strong&gt;why&lt;/strong&gt;”—a lesson that has guided her throughout her career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-first-career-step&quot;&gt;The First Career Step&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Valerie’s career began as a software engineer for a consulting company, where she developed custom software. This experience was pivotal in shaping her career trajectory. “I learned so much about technology in school, but my first job kickstarted my passion for understanding business requirements and opportunities,” Valerie recalls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of her key takeaways from this early experience was the importance of focusing on &lt;strong&gt;why, who, and what&lt;/strong&gt; before jumping into the &lt;strong&gt;how&lt;/strong&gt;. “Too often, failure happens because the ‘why’ is not fully understood,” she notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;strategies-that-work&quot;&gt;Strategies That Work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Landing her first job was no accident. Valerie credits a combination of &lt;strong&gt;networking&lt;/strong&gt;, building an &lt;strong&gt;online brand&lt;/strong&gt;, and leveraging &lt;strong&gt;job postings&lt;/strong&gt; as strategies that helped her break into the tech industry. Her experience underscores the importance of being proactive and using multiple approaches when job hunting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lessons-from-the-journey&quot;&gt;Lessons from the Journey&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Valerie’s career journey has been shaped by valuable insights and mindset shifts, such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Always seek to understand &lt;strong&gt;why&lt;/strong&gt; before tackling how.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t shy away from failure; view it as a stepping stone, not a permanent setback.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keep learning and stay curious.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;college-experience-a-foundation-for-growth&quot;&gt;College Experience: A Foundation for Growth&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Valerie, college wasn’t just about academics—it was also about preparing for the real world. While working her way through school, she developed critical time-management skills and gained early career exposure. However, Valerie also emphasizes the importance of engaging with the &lt;strong&gt;social aspects of college life&lt;/strong&gt;, as these experiences help build networks and develop interpersonal skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;words-of-wisdom-for-the-next-generation&quot;&gt;Words of Wisdom for the Next Generation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Valerie’s advice for students is both simple and profound:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Always have fun.&lt;/strong&gt; Find joy in what you do, no matter where you are in your career.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be courageous.&lt;/strong&gt; Take risks and lean into challenges.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Never compromise who you are.&lt;/strong&gt; Authenticity is key to long-term success.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-final-thought&quot;&gt;A Final Thought&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Valerie Bergman’s journey shows that a fulfilling career is about more than just landing a job—it’s about aligning your skills, passions, and values. For college juniors planning their futures, her story serves as a powerful reminder to focus on the “why” behind their career choices, embrace continuous learning, and take bold steps toward their goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let Valerie’s advice be your guide as you embark on your career journey—and remember, every failed attempt is simply a stepping stone toward success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’d love to spot light you.  Tell us your story at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sujeeth.org/stories&quot;&gt;https://www.sujeeth.org/stories&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="spotlight" /><summary type="html">Discover valuable career tips for students through Valerie Bergman&apos;s inspiring journey from software engineer to Microsoft Field Sales Specialist. Learn how aligning passion with profession, strategic networking, and continuous learning can help you navigate your career path. Get practical advice on building experience, embracing challenges, and staying authentic.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Yes Now, Learn It Later: Britt Hall</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Britt-Hall/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Yes Now, Learn It Later: Britt Hall" /><published>2025-03-06T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2025-03-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Britt-Hall</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Britt-Hall/">&lt;p&gt;The Sujeeth Foundation Spotlight highlights the stories of individuals who made the jump from academia to industry.  We share stories to inspire and educate.  We hope students can leverage this experience in their own journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For many college juniors, the uncertainty of what comes next can be overwhelming. You might be wondering if your major is the right fit, how to land your first job, or whether the twists and turns of your journey will lead to success. To offer some inspiration, we’re sharing the story of Britt Hall—a professional who carved out a fulfilling career by embracing change, saying “yes” to opportunities, and staying true to their values.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Britt Hall’s career has been a journey of transformation, adaptability, and storytelling. She began in journalism, leading student newspapers and shaping narratives that connected communities. That passion for communication and culture led her into corporate environments, where she built internal communications strategies, fostered engagement, and helped organizations navigate change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Whole Foods Market, Britt played a key role in launching the 365 brand, designing team member experiences and driving internal culture. At National Instruments, she partnered with senior leaders to implement large-scale transformation and modern workplace initiatives. Now, at Cisco, she leads global enablement efforts, ensuring talent strategies empower people and teams to thrive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through every step, Britt’s work has been shaped by three guiding values: authenticity, accountability, and creative problem-solving. She remains dedicated to building meaningful experiences that drive impact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-first-steps-a-nonlinear-college-journey&quot;&gt;The First Steps: A Nonlinear College Journey&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Britt Hall’s college experience wasn’t a straight path. In fact, it took nearly seven years to complete a bachelor’s degree. Initially pursuing music education and performance, Britt found themselves on an expected trajectory—until a single elective, “Storytelling and Puppetry,” reshaped their perspective. That class ignited a passion for storytelling, leading to a major shift into journalism and communications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Switching from a music program meant starting over, even taking a step back to community college before transferring again on a journalism scholarship. These experiences taught Britt valuable lessons in resilience, adaptability, and trusting one’s instincts—skills that would prove crucial in their career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-first-job-freelance-hustle-and-saying-yes&quot;&gt;The First Job: Freelance, Hustle, and Saying Yes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Britt’s first job after college wasn’t handed to them—it was built through experience and opportunity. While freelancing for the Corpus Christi Caller-Times, Britt wore many hats: general assignments reporter, copy editor, and even interim archivist. At the same time, they worked as a barista, eventually taking on training and marketing roles for the coffee shop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three months after graduation, Britt secured their first full-time role in marketing and communications for the Corpus Christi Symphony Orchestra—an opportunity that came from an earlier internship. The key lesson? Keep doors open, maintain good relationships, and recognize that every experience (even in retail and food service) builds skills that matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-career-built-on-passion-and-adaptability&quot;&gt;A Career Built on Passion and Adaptability&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to today, Britt leads a global team at Cisco, managing employee experience and enablement for hiring and internal talent movement programs. It’s a role that aligns almost perfectly with their Ikigai—the Japanese concept of purpose—combining passion, mission, vocation, and profession.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Britt’s journey from journalism to corporate leadership wasn’t accidental. It was guided by a mindset of embracing change, being willing to “figure it out,” and leveraging past experiences to build a unique and valuable career path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;advice-for-college-juniors-be-a-bricoleur&quot;&gt;Advice for College Juniors: Be a Bricoleur&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what advice does Britt have for students entering the workforce?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Say yes now, figure it out later.&lt;/strong&gt; Opportunities don’t always come neatly packaged. Trust yourself enough to take on challenges, even when you don’t feel fully prepared.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Build resilience.&lt;/strong&gt; The most adaptable and successful people share three traits: accepting reality, finding meaning in what they do, and improvising when necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Identify your values early.&lt;/strong&gt; Britt’s guiding principles—authenticity, accountability, and creative problem-solving—help in making decisions, setting boundaries, and maintaining work-life balance.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keep relationships strong.&lt;/strong&gt; The first full-time job came from an internship, and career growth often hinges on connections and a strong reputation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-takeaway-your-path-is-yours-to-make&quot;&gt;The Takeaway: Your Path is Yours to Make&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Britt Hall’s career isn’t one of rigid planning—it’s a testament to adaptability, lifelong learning, and saying “yes” to the right opportunities. For college juniors feeling uncertain, the message is clear: your path doesn’t have to be linear. Trust the journey, embrace change, and build a career that aligns with your passions and strengths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, as you plan your next steps, remember—you have the power to shape your own story, just like Britt Hall did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’d love to spot light you.  Tell us your story at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sujeeth.org/stories&quot;&gt;https://www.sujeeth.org/stories&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="spotlight" /><summary type="html">Explore Britt Hall&apos;s inspiring career journey from journalism to corporate leadership. Learn how adaptability, resilience, and strategic networking helped her succeed. Discover practical tips for students on building experience, embracing change, and aligning their careers with their passions and strengths.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Prepare and Adapt: Dave D’Abate</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Dave-Dabate/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Prepare and Adapt: Dave D’Abate" /><published>2025-03-06T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2025-03-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Dave-Dabate</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Dave-Dabate/">&lt;p&gt;The Sujeeth Foundation Spotlight highlights the stories of individuals who made the jump from academia to industry.  We share stories to inspire and educate.  We hope students can leverage this experience in their own journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For college juniors preparing to launch their careers, the path ahead can feel both exciting and uncertain. How do you land that first job? What skills truly matter? How do you turn a job into a fulfilling career? To help answer these questions, we spoke with Dave D’Abate, a successful Account Executive whose career journey is proof that relationships, continuous learning, and adaptability are key ingredients for long-term success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;starting-strong-lessons-from-the-first-job&quot;&gt;Starting Strong: Lessons from the First Job&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dave’s career began at AT&amp;amp;T as a retail sales consultant. Like many fresh graduates, he started in an entry-level role, selling devices and services to both consumers and small business accounts. But what set him apart? His mindset. While others simply met expectations, Dave aimed higher—doubling his sales targets and positioning himself as a go-to resource and subject matter expert.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He quickly learned that success isn’t just about showing up; it’s about being proactive. “I had to put in the effort beyond what I witnessed from my colleagues,” he says. This willingness to go the extra mile became a defining trait in his career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;breaking-into-the-workforce-the-power-of-first-impressions&quot;&gt;Breaking into the Workforce: The Power of First Impressions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Landing that first job can be daunting, but Dave emphasizes the importance of energy, enthusiasm, and preparation. One piece of advice he received early on has stuck with him: “Every conversation you have is an interview.” From the very first screening call to the final handshake, the way you present yourself matters. Being able to articulate your work ethic and passion can make all the difference in standing out to hiring managers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;building-a-career-key-lessons-and-mindset-shifts&quot;&gt;Building a Career: Key Lessons and Mindset Shifts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the years, Dave has picked up several insights that have fueled his success:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be willing to learn.&lt;/strong&gt; Taking the extra time to do something correctly now will set you up for success later.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Manage your business.&lt;/strong&gt; If something needs to get done, schedule time for it—otherwise, it won’t happen.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adaptability is key.&lt;/strong&gt; You won’t always succeed on the first try, but the ability to adjust and improve will make you stronger.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incorporate feedback immediately.&lt;/strong&gt; When someone offers guidance, show them that their investment in you is worth it by implementing changes right away.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;from-college-to-career-the-importance-of-preparation&quot;&gt;From College to Career: The Importance of Preparation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dave admits that he wasn’t the best student in college—he spent more time hiking than studying. But he quickly realized that preparation is everything. “Studying in college is very similar to how one should prepare before any meeting,” he explains. Whether it’s a class or a client presentation, showing up unprepared is never an option. Observing how others operate and borrowing their best practices can help you refine your own approach over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;final-advice-for-students-entering-the-workforce&quot;&gt;Final Advice for Students Entering the Workforce&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dave’s parting wisdom for students is simple yet powerful: “Always set aside time to continue investing in your success.” Seek out mentors who are invested in your growth, absorb their knowledge, and apply it. But never stop learning—if you ever find yourself as the smartest person in the room, it’s time to find a different room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you chart your own career path, remember that success isn’t a straight line. It’s built on hard work, adaptability, and the relationships you nurture along the way. Take a page from Dave D’Abate’s journey, and embrace every opportunity to learn and grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’d love to spot light you.  Tell us your story at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sujeeth.org/stories&quot;&gt;https://www.sujeeth.org/stories&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="spotlight" /><summary type="html">Explore Dave D&apos;Abate&apos;s inspiring career journey from retail sales consultant at AT&amp;T to Account Executive. Learn how relationships, continuous learning, and adaptability helped him succeed. Discover practical tips for students on building experience, embracing challenges, and navigating their career paths effectively.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Start Small: Laurel Dzneladze</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Laurel-Dzneladze/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Start Small: Laurel Dzneladze" /><published>2025-03-06T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2025-03-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Laurel-Dzneladze</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Laurel-Dzneladze/">&lt;p&gt;The Sujeeth Foundation Spotlight highlights the stories of individuals who made the jump from academia to industry.  We share stories to inspire and educate.  We hope students can leverage this experience in their own journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Planning your career might seem daunting, but learning from those who have navigated similar paths can be both inspiring and insightful. One such story is that of Laurel Dzneladze, a dynamic professional at Microsoft whose journey showcases the power of adaptability, networking, and continuous learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;finding-passion-through-experience&quot;&gt;Finding Passion Through Experience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Laurel currently supports the Microsoft Viva Community and communication products, focusing on product marketing and go-to-market strategies. Her passion lies in how community and communications shape an organization’s success. Throughout her career, she has dedicated herself to building solutions that drive engagement, productivity, and overall success within companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her career trajectory wasn’t a straight line, but each experience helped shape her professional path. Laurel’s story is proof that discovering your Ikigai—the intersection of passion, mission, vocation, and profession—takes time, experimentation, and a willingness to explore different opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;from-internship-to-full-time-success&quot;&gt;From Internship to Full-Time Success&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Laurel’s first job came as an extension of an internship at Johnson Controls, which transitioned into a full-time role after graduation. In this position, she was responsible for communicating large organizational changes and managing digital spaces like the company’s website and intranet.
Some of her most valuable lessons from this early experience included:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Understanding organizational processes&lt;/strong&gt;—how to start and complete a project effectively.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Developing presentation and executive relationship skills&lt;/strong&gt;—key abilities that help in gaining visibility and trust.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Collaborating in a corporate environment&lt;/strong&gt;—learning how to navigate teams and work cross-functionally.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;landing-the-first-job-a-lesson-in-proactive-networking&quot;&gt;Landing the First Job: A Lesson in Proactive Networking&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How did Laurel secure her internship that led to her first job? It started with an unpaid marketing role at a performing arts foundation, where she dedicated just four hours a week. That experience gave her exposure to a network of professionals, including board members who later connected her with the internship opportunity at Johnson Controls.
Her journey highlights a crucial strategy:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Start small, be proactive, and leverage networking opportunities. Even the smallest roles can lead to significant career breakthroughs when approached with the right mindset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;career-lessons-and-mindset-shifts&quot;&gt;Career Lessons and Mindset Shifts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout her career, Laurel has embraced a mindset of continuous learning and adaptability. Here are some of her key insights:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Share ideas early and often&lt;/strong&gt;—don’t be afraid to put your thoughts out there.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ask questions instead of disagreeing outright&lt;/strong&gt;—a great approach to constructive discussions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Observe and learn from leadership&lt;/strong&gt;—find role models whose work ethic and leadership style resonate with you.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Look beyond your immediate team&lt;/strong&gt;—seek projects outside your role that expose you to new challenges and learning opportunities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;embracing-a-nonlinear-path&quot;&gt;Embracing a Nonlinear Path&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Laurel’s college experience was anything but conventional. She started as a dance major in Kansas City, studied abroad for a year, then took time off before resuming college at 25 years old. She compressed 2.5 years of coursework into just 1.5 years, proving that determination and flexibility can reshape one’s academic and career path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This unconventional journey reinforced an important lesson: careers are not always linear. The skills and experiences you gain from varied paths can become assets in unexpected ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;advice-for-college-students&quot;&gt;Advice for College Students&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If Laurel could give one piece of advice to students entering the workforce, it would be:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Not every role needs to be your dream job, and not every company needs to be your dream company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s okay to change your mind about your career direction multiple times. What matters is gaining clarity on what excites you and where you want to grow after spending time in the workforce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Takeaways for Your Career Journey
Laurel Dzneladze’s story is a testament to the power of &lt;strong&gt;persistence, adaptability, and strategic networking&lt;/strong&gt;. Whether you’re just starting out or rethinking your path, remember that &lt;strong&gt;every experience adds value&lt;/strong&gt;—even the unexpected ones. Your journey is uniquely yours, and with an open mind and proactive approach, you can carve a fulfilling and successful career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s your next step?&lt;/strong&gt; Start small, be open to opportunities, and don’t be afraid to take the unconventional path—it might just lead you exactly where you need to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’d love to spot light you.  Tell us your story at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sujeeth.org/stories&quot;&gt;https://www.sujeeth.org/stories&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="spotlight" /><summary type="html">Explore Laurel Dzneladze&apos;s inspiring career journey from an unpaid marketing role to a full-time position at Johnson Controls. Learn how adaptability, networking, and continuous learning helped her succeed. Discover practical tips for students on building experience, embracing challenges, and navigating their career paths effectively.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Adaptability: Michelle Leaverton</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Michelle-Leaverton/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Adaptability: Michelle Leaverton" /><published>2025-03-06T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2025-03-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Michelle-Leaverton</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Michelle-Leaverton/">&lt;p&gt;The Sujeeth Foundation Spotlight highlights the stories of individuals who made the jump from academia to industry.  We share stories to inspire and educate.  We hope students can leverage this experience in their own journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some career paths are straightforward, while others, like Michelle Leaverton’s, weave through diverse industries and experiences, culminating in a skillset that defies categorization. From corporate project management to nonprofit leadership and ministry, Michelle’s journey exemplifies resilience, adaptability, and a deep commitment to making an impact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-career-spanning-corporate-nonprofit-and-religious-sectors&quot;&gt;A Career Spanning Corporate, Nonprofit, and Religious Sectors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Michelle’s professional story is one of transformation and versatility. She recently held a role as an Advisor in Project and Program Management at Dell Technologies, where she worked in the Global Presales PMO. Over 2.5 years, she spearheaded global-scale enablement programs, process improvements, and career development initiatives for a workforce of over 5,000 professionals. Her ability to drive complex projects with creativity and collaboration made her an invaluable asset to the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before Dell, Michelle dedicated much of her career to nonprofit and ministry work, reflecting her passion for community engagement and social impact. She served as the Youth and Social Impact Director at Westminster Presbyterian Church, where she designed and managed youth programs, mission trips, and outreach initiatives addressing food insecurity, homelessness, and immigrant support. Her leadership in coordinating volunteers for Meals on Wheels during the pandemic further demonstrated her ability to mobilize communities in times of need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-new-chapter-entrepreneurship-and-communication-expertise&quot;&gt;A New Chapter: Entrepreneurship and Communication Expertise&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In August 2024, Michelle launched Collateral Designs, a business specializing in polished presentations and impactful communications. Her firm offers services that enhance clarity, creativity, and professionalism in business materials—helping clients craft compelling messages and visuals that stand out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Michelle’s expertise in communication, project development, and strategic planning positions her uniquely at the intersection of corporate efficiency and nonprofit passion. She holds a Bachelor of Arts in Russian Studies and Environmental Studies from the University of Kansas and a Master of Arts in Christian Education from Union Presbyterian Seminary. Her diverse academic background underscores her ability to think across disciplines and adapt to new challenges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;resilience-through-lifes-challenges&quot;&gt;Resilience Through Life’s Challenges&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond her professional achievements, Michelle’s personal journey is marked by resilience and growth. She and her husband, Rod, have spent the past decade rebuilding their lives after the loss of their first spouses to cancer. Through grief and joy, they’ve forged a new path, embracing life with their blended family and continuing to make a difference in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bringing-fresh-perspectives-to-every-opportunity&quot;&gt;Bringing Fresh Perspectives to Every Opportunity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether managing global programs, leading nonprofit initiatives, or helping businesses refine their messaging, Michelle Leaverton approaches every challenge with a problem-solving mindset. Her ability to adapt, learn, and lead across sectors is a testament to the power of a diverse career path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking for someone who can blend corporate strategy with a heart for mission-driven work, Michelle is a name to remember.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’d love to spot light you.  Tell us your story at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sujeeth.org/stories&quot;&gt;https://www.sujeeth.org/stories&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="spotlight" /><summary type="html">Explore Michelle Leaverton&apos;s inspiring career journey from academia to industry, showcasing her resilience and adaptability. Learn how she transitioned from corporate project management at Dell Technologies to nonprofit leadership and ministry, and eventually launched her own business, Collateral Designs. Discover practical tips for students on building experience, embracing challenges, and making a positive impact in their professional lives.</summary></entry></feed>