<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-06-08T19:12:43-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">The Sujeeth Foundation - Scholarships</title><subtitle>Unlocking opportunity through education. The Sujeeth Foundation provides  scholarships, training, and other services to college students. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Using Generative AI to Explore Career Opportunities</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/career/Using-Generative-AI-to-explore-career-opportunities/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Using Generative AI to Explore Career Opportunities" /><published>2023-06-03T01:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-06-03T01:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/career/Using-Generative-AI-to-explore-career-opportunities</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/career/Using-Generative-AI-to-explore-career-opportunities/">&lt;p&gt;In the pursuit of a fulfilling career, Angela Duckworth’s wisdom on early exploration and cultivating passion resonates deeply. She reminds us that the path to finding our true calling requires more than just picking a job; it demands an open mind, an adventurous spirit, and a willingness to embrace unexpected opportunities. By exploring different career paths, understanding that passion can be developed, and aligning with our core values, we set the stage for a transformative journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are your interests?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;interests are not discovered through introspection. Instead, interests are triggered by interactions with the outside world. The process of interest discovery can be messy, serendipitous, and inefficient. This is because you can’t really predict with certainty what will capture your attention and what won’t. You can’t simply will yourself to like things, either. As Jeff Bezos has observed, “One of the huge mistakes people make is that they try to force an interest on themselves.” Without experimenting, you can’t figure out which interests will stick, and which won’t. (Grit: The Power of Passion and Perserverance)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Duckworth’s emphasis on exploration serves as a powerful reminder that our passions are not predetermined or fixed. Rather, they emerge through a process of discovery and intentional exploration. We are invited to step outside our comfort zones and immerse ourselves in a world of possibilities, allowing curiosity to guide our journey. By venturing into unfamiliar territories, we open ourselves up to the serendipitous encounters and unexpected passions that can shape our career trajectory in extraordinary ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trying out various interests and being open to new experiences aligns perfectly with the essence of generative AI. This cutting-edge technology leverages the power of machine learning to generate new ideas, concepts, and possibilities. It can assist individuals in exploring diverse career paths, unveiling uncharted territories, and uncovering hidden talents that may have remained dormant otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While preparing for the launch of the programs portal, I completed a scholarship application.  As part of the process, my application was screened by Azure Open AI and I was provided feedback and job recommendations.  I was surprised by some of the options that were suggested to me.  In fact, I’m consistently surprised by the depth and breadth of questions that ChatGPT will respond to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to deeply explore a the “systems analyst” job suggestions to get ideas of what the job entails and how I could potentially prepare for the interview.  I learned that I could prepare through online courses at Coursera and edX, that Accenture may be a company willing to hire a business major, and that I should explore a student membership with the Association for Information Systems.  Along the way, I also got information that would help me prepare for informational interviews like “can I be system analyst if I don’t know how to program?”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It strikes me that if I’m curious a short conversation can provide a lot of information that can make it easier to interact with the outside world.  At least it gives me a start.  I’m sharing to provide some inspiration of how others can use Generative AI to get more out of the feedback provided by the scholarship process.  You can see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://chat.openai.com/share/7563a68b-e271-4d88-800f-bdd590b0a998&quot;&gt;full conversation&lt;/a&gt;; below I’m sharing the questions I asked and my motivation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What does the career trajectory for system analyst look like over ten years?
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I like understanding the end game.  Starting with the end mind helps me envision if this is a path I want to invest in.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do people normally stay in technology roles or are there opportunities to transition to other functions?
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Even now, I’m an technology apologist - I’m much more interested in the business problems that technology can solve.  I ask question to try to get a deeper understanding of opportunity outside of IT.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What other roles do system analysts work with?  What other functions?
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I didn’t like the first answer, four of the six options revolved around technology so I thought I would reframe to ask again.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What does a day to day of a System Analyst looks like?
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Regardless of the end state, I think it’s important to like your job.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What are the top companies that hire system analysts?
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;This is an amazing question.  Getting this list really helps make discovery actionable.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What are ways that I can network with the above companies to get a job interview for a system analyst position?
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I use this question to brainstorm on actions that I can take.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What professional associations and meetups for system analysts are available for college students to join?
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;One of the most surprising things for me when working Artificial Generative Intelligence is the depth that you can get ask answers.  If you want more details, ask.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Looking at the list of 20 companies above and these five associations can you create table that indicates the company name and the association that they are a member of?
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I’m using the question to help prioritize my time.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How can college students get involved with the Association for Information Systems?
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I’m using this question brainstorm appropriate actions.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I don’t have experience in an IT environment.  How can I get that experience as a college student or through AIS?
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I’m using this question to brainstorm on ways I could meet job requirements when I graduate.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What are online courses and certifications that are available for system analyst roles that I should look at?
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I’m looking at another way of meeting job requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are any of the above free or discounted for college students?  Are there YouTube videos that you can recommend?  Basically I’m looking for resources that can get me started.
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I’m looking for actions I can do now.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Looking at the list of 20 companies above, what colleges do they recruit from?  What colleges also participate in the Association of Information Systems?
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I think the insight you can get from this question is really interesting.  Accenture stood out from the list because they are willing ot interview talent from non-traditional degrees.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What schools do the below hire from?
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;In a long conversation, Artificial Generative Intelligence will get lost.  Providing details can get the conversation back on track.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What are the job requirements for a systems analyst at Accenture?
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Getting very specific can lead to interesting insight.  This is the first time Technical Skills came up.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are there specific Coursera or edX courses that you can consider to learn about the software development life cycle?
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Likewise, being very specific can lead to actionable advice.  This helps prioritize time.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this exploration is useful, validation of interests only happens in the real world.  Generative AI is a compliment to traditional ways of preparing for a career - it helps surface blind spots and prioritize efforts.  It’s important to actively engage with the outside world, take risks, and pursue opportunities that resonate with you. By combining curiosity, exploration, and the insights gained from generative AI, you can embark on a transformative journey towards a fulfilling and meaningful career.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="career" /><summary type="html">Generative AI, like ChatGPT, can serve as a valuable tool in career exploration by providing insights and recommendations. It can help individuals uncover potential paths, discover resources such as online courses and professional associations, and prioritize efforts based on personalized feedback. However, while generative AI is beneficial, it should be complemented by real-world engagement, taking risks, and pursuing opportunities to validate and develop interests for a truly fulfilling career journey.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Work Out Loud Archives</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/career/Work-Out-Loud-Archives/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Work Out Loud Archives" /><published>2023-06-03T01:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-06-03T01:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/career/Work-Out-Loud-Archives</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/career/Work-Out-Loud-Archives/">&lt;p&gt;Every day we’re making a lot of progress to launching the scholarship.  In addition to providing funds, one of the goals of the foundation is to enrich the experience of every applicant.  To that end, welcome gifts, volunteering opportunities, community meetups and even the application for the scholarship itself – they are all targeted to help applicants build skills in Mindset, Grit, and Working Out Loud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working Out Loud is a concept coined by John Stepper.  In today’s interconnected and fast-paced world, success is not solely determined by individual brilliance or expertise; it thrives on collaboration, community, and the power of networks. Enter “Work Out Loud” (WOL), a transformative approach that empowers professionals to harness the full potential of collaboration, share their work openly, and cultivate meaningful connections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At its core, WOL is a mindset and practice that encourages individuals to make their work visible, actively contribute to the success of others, and build purposeful networks. It is a departure from traditional silos and closed-door practices, ushering in a new era of transparency, generosity, and collective growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this digital age, where information flows freely and barriers to communication have diminished, the power of working out loud has become more evident than ever. By sharing our ideas, progress, and challenges with a wider audience, we tap into the collective intelligence of our networks and unlock opportunities for collaboration, feedback, and learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, WOL is not just about broadcasting our work; it’s about building relationships that transcend geographical boundaries and professional hierarchies. It’s about finding like-minded individuals, diverse perspectives, and unexpected collaborations that fuel innovation and drive personal and organizational growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John even created a guide to help people facilitate their own work out loud circles.  I envision where a community will build around the Sujeeth Foundation and we will be able to connect applicants to each other as they strive to determine their passion and achieve their purpose.  To help with that community building I’ve gathered John’s guides in this blog post:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/wol/wol-circle-guides-v4.5-week-1.pdf&quot;&gt;Week 1: Attune your attention&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
In your first week, after getting to know your other Circle members a bit better, each of you will pick your own individual goal. Then you’ll take a step towards that goal by creating a “relationship list,” an initial list of people related to your goal.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/wol/wol-circle-guides-v4.5-week-2.pdf&quot;&gt;Week 2: Offer your first contributions&lt;/a&gt;
In Week 2, you’ll make simple contributions to people on your relationship list, deepening relationships in a small way. Just reviewing the list will further attune your attention to your goal, and the small steps you take each week will gradually increase your sense of empowerment.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/wol/wol-circle-guides-v4.5-week-3.pdf&quot;&gt;Week 3: Take three small steps&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
In Week 3, you’ll make a simple adjustment to managing your time, you’ll add to your relationship list, and you’ll offer another kind of contribution. These small steps will help reinforce and expand your practice.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/wol/wol-circle-guides-v4.5-week-4.pdf&quot;&gt;Week 4: Earn someone else’s attention&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
How you present your contribution can make all the difference. This week, you’ll practice refining the way you write your messages and how you approach people in general. These exercises will make your contributions feel more personal and valuable, and more likely to be effective.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/wol/wol-circle-guides-v4.5-week-5.pdf&quot;&gt;Week 5: Make it personal&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Most people think far too narrowly about what they have to offer. This week can change that for you. The exercises will help you understand how the broad set of things you may take for granted - what makes you you - can serve as the basis for meaningful connections with others.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/wol/wol-circle-guides-v4.5-week-6.pdf&quot;&gt;Week 6: Improve your visibility&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
It’s hard for anyone to discover you and your work when you’re invisible. This week, to improve your chances of making connections, you’ll take a step towards improving your online presence. Then you’ll use your improved presence to deepen a relationship.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/wol/wol-circle-guides-v4.5-week-7.pdf&quot;&gt;Week 7: Be purposeful&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
This week, you’ll do one of the most powerful exercises in your Circle: “A letter from your future self.” By articulating a longer-term vision of what might be possible, you‘ll increase the chances of that vision becoming a reality.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/wol/wol-circle-guides-v4.5-week-8.pdf&quot;&gt;Week 8: Make it a habit&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Although you’ve spent seven weeks thinking of your goal in terms of people and contributions, you’re still working on making it a habit and mindset. It’s natural, for example, to struggle with finding time to work your list or remembering to follow up. This week, you’ll explore ways to reinforce your new habit so it takes less effort and feels increasingly natural, and to overcome the inevitable challenges and setbacks. Then you’ll practice empathy (again) in a way that might surprise you - and will certainly distinguish you.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/wol/wol-circle-guides-v4.5-week-9.pdf&quot;&gt;Week 9: Explore more original contributions&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
At this point in your Circle, you’re ready to further expand your range of contributions by making more of your work and thinking visible. Even if this is new to some of you or makes you uncomfortable, the exercises this week will help you take a step, allowing you to create something simple that’s also generous and useful.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/wol/wol-circle-guides-v4.5-week-10.pdf&quot;&gt;Week 10: Become more systematic&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Having a system can make things easier. This week, you’ll work with two simple systems, one for identifying new contributions and one for managing your relationship list. Then you’ll offer something which you may never have thought of as a contribution.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/wol/wol-circle-guides-v4.5-week-11.pdf&quot;&gt;Week 11: Imagine the possibilities&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
So far, the focus has been on your individual contributions and connections. In Week 11, you’ll expand your sense of what’s possible by thinking more broadly about your network, your role in it, and what you might accomplish together.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/wol/wol-circle-guides-v4.5-week-12.pdf&quot;&gt;Week 12: Reflect and celebrate&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
This final week marks the end of a process, and maybe a kind of beginning. You’ll reflect on what has changed for you and what might
come. In your last exercise, you’ll make several additional contributions, including some for yourself. Hold this final meeting over lunch or dinner if you can - or come up with some other creative way to create an environment that’s conducive to celebration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="career" /><summary type="html">The Sujeeth Foundation is committed to enriching the experience of every scholarship applicant by focusing on mindset, grit, and working out loud. We aim to facilitate community building among the applicants. To support this vision, I have gathered John Stepper&apos;s WOL guides, which provide a structured approach for individuals to implement the WOL practice. These guides span a twelve-week period and cover various aspects of building relationships, making contributions, refining communication, improving visibility, articulating a vision, developing habits, and expanding one&apos;s network.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Sujeeth Foundation starts today</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/announcements/Unlock-the-Opportunity-of-Education/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Sujeeth Foundation starts today" /><published>2023-05-16T01:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-05-16T01:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/announcements/Unlock-the-Opportunity-of-Education</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/announcements/Unlock-the-Opportunity-of-Education/">&lt;p&gt;This week I filed the paperwork to start the Sujeeth Foundation.  I want to use the foundation to unlock the opportunity of education.  Education can train our youth to undertake professions that can enrich their lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, education is broken:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Only 34% of workers in the US are engaged. This means that most people are not happy with their jobs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Student borrowers accumulated nearly $30,000 in undergraduate debt. This debt can be a burden for years after graduation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It doesn’t have to be this way:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Teaching youth growth mindset unlocks the potential for development.  Failure is part of success and embracing failure helps people take risks that lead to change.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Passion for what you do stems from learning what you do well and investing to develop your skills to solve a meaningful problem.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;At their best, academic institutions are a place where experimentation thrives and opportunities to grow are abundant.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The mindset of the student matters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Sujeeth Foundation provides scholarships to college students pursuing a STEM degree or graduate studies.  Scholarships are awarded based on Grit scores.  All applicants can take advantage of provided growth mindset training and other services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was raised in a family that believed in education.  I was told that if I studied hard, I would be recruited by employers and be ushered into a rewarding career.  The formula for success was simple - get good grades.  I ended up earning my B.A. in Economics from Saint Louis University in three frantic years.  During that time I also worked to support myself.  I didn’t sleep very much.  I also didn’t spend a significant amount of the time in the career center.  At the end of three years, I went to work at a call center.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt that the promise was broken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In hindsight, I realized that I missed the point.  People don’t hire you because of what you have done, they hire you because of what they think you can do.  I couldn’t say what I wanted to do.  I couldn’t explain how my skills were valuable.  I didn’t have a framework to launch a career from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later, I went back to school full time to earn my MBA from Washington University.  This time I was focused on entering consulting.  I had a clear picture that I needed to show that my accounting and analytic skills could contribute to a consulting team.  I eventually found a home at Microsoft that my valued my analytic skills, my technical propensity, and my sales experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a moment, the opportunity I received changed my stars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This organization, this effort, is my attempt to pay forward the opportunity I was given.  I want to help people get jobs they love.  I think school is a great way to accomplish that if you keep the goal in focus.  That is why I filed the paperwork.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="announcements" /><summary type="html">This is the origin story of the Sujeeth Foundation. The mission is to unlock the opportunity of education. The foundation provides scholarships to college students pursuing a STEM degree or graduate studies. Scholarships are awarded based on Grit scores. All applicants can take advantage of provided growth mindset training and other services.</summary></entry></feed>