<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-04-23T05:28:57+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">The Sujeeth Foundation</title><subtitle>Unlocking opportunity through education. The Sujeeth Foundation helps students network into their first job. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Coat of Arms</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/career/coat-of-arms/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Coat of Arms" /><published>2025-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/career/coat-of-arms</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/career/coat-of-arms/"><![CDATA[<h3 id="finding-your-purpose-a-journey-through-your-past-present-and-future">Finding Your Purpose: A Journey Through Your Past, Present, and Future</h3>

<p><strong>Introduction</strong></p>

<p>College is more than just picking a major or landing an internship—it’s a time to ask big questions. One of the biggest: <em>“What’s my purpose?”</em></p>

<p>Knowing your purpose isn’t about having your whole life mapped out. It’s about getting clearer on what drives you—what matters to you—and using that insight to make better choices, build meaningful relationships, and open the right doors. In this post, we’ll show you how to begin discovering your purpose by reflecting on your past and connecting it to where you are today and where you want to go.</p>

<p>One of the best tools to help? An exercise called <strong>“Build Your Coat of Arms.”</strong> It’s simple, but powerful. Let’s dive in.</p>

<hr />

<h3 id="understanding-purpose">Understanding Purpose</h3>

<p>Your purpose is the thread that connects what you care about, what you’re good at, and what impact you want to make. It’s what gets you up in the morning—or would, if you had more clarity.</p>

<p>But purpose doesn’t just show up one day. You find it through reflection: by looking at your experiences, recognizing your strengths, and naming the values that guide your decisions. That’s how you start to see patterns—and possibilities.</p>

<hr />

<h3 id="connecting-purpose-to-your-past">Connecting Purpose to Your Past</h3>

<p>Your past holds clues about your future. Here’s how to mine those insights:</p>

<ol>
  <li><strong>Spot the Key Moments</strong>: Think back over the past 10 years. What experiences shaped you? What moments were joyful, painful, surprising, or proud?</li>
  <li><strong>Look for Themes</strong>: Are there common threads—subjects that always excite you, causes you care about, skills you keep using? Successes and failures can both reveal where your energy naturally flows.</li>
  <li><strong>Name Your Values</strong>: What mattered most to you in those moments? Integrity? Creativity? Helping others? Achievement? These values often point directly to your purpose.</li>
</ol>

<hr />

<h3 id="try-this-build-your-coat-of-arms">Try This: Build Your Coat of Arms</h3>

<p>This reflection exercise helps you look at your life through a meaningful lens—your story, your now, and your next.</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>10 Years Ago</strong>: Where were you? What shaped your identity? How did you see the world then, and how have you grown?</li>
  <li><strong>Today</strong>: What strengths and values define you now? What do people rely on you for? What energizes or drains you?</li>
  <li><strong>5 Years from Now</strong>: What kind of life do you want to be living? What kind of work feels meaningful? What steps could move you in that direction?</li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p><em>This simple exercise can clarify more than you expect. When you start sharing your story from this perspective, people listen—and often want to help.</em></p>
</blockquote>

<hr />

<h3 id="principle-self-awareness-leads-to-clarity">Principle: Self-Awareness Leads to Clarity</h3>

<p>You don’t need to have it all figured out. But the more self-aware you are, the easier it is to make confident decisions, attract support, and pursue opportunities that fit <em>you</em>—not someone else’s idea of success.</p>

<hr />

<h3 id="reminder-purpose-is-iterative">Reminder: Purpose is Iterative</h3>

<p>You’re not locking in your entire future here. Purpose evolves. It deepens as you grow, stumble, and try new things. That’s a good thing. It means you don’t have to be perfect—you just have to keep learning.</p>

<p>These two ideas can help you keep going:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Growth Mindset</strong>: Believe you can grow your abilities through effort and feedback. Challenges aren’t roadblocks—they’re stepping stones.</li>
  <li><strong>Grit</strong>: Stick with your goals, even when it’s hard. Grit isn’t about never failing—it’s about not giving up when you do.</li>
</ul>

<hr />

<h3 id="why-it-matters-now">Why It Matters Now</h3>

<p>Clarity about your purpose doesn’t just help you feel better—it helps you <strong>take action</strong>. It makes your job search more focused. Your LinkedIn profile more compelling. Your conversations more memorable.</p>

<p>And perhaps most importantly: when <strong>you</strong> understand what you’re about, it becomes easier for <strong>others</strong> to support you, mentor you, and open doors.</p>

<hr />

<h3 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h3>

<p>Finding your purpose isn’t a one-time event—it’s a practice. The more you reflect on your story, the clearer your direction becomes.</p>

<p>Start with the “Build Your Coat of Arms” exercise. Give yourself the gift of reflection. Then, start sharing what you’re learning—with mentors, friends, and your community. Because purpose isn’t just something you find. It’s something you build, over time, with courage and curiosity.</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>👉 Want to go deeper?</strong> Try the Coat of Arms exercise and post it in our LinkedIn cohort group. You might be surprised who connects with your story.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="career" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Students can uncover purpose and direction by reflecting on their past, present, and future using the 'Build Your Coat of Arms' exercise.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Network with ChatGPT</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/career/network-with-chatgpt/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Network with ChatGPT" /><published>2025-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/career/network-with-chatgpt</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/career/network-with-chatgpt/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="building-your-brand-on-linkedin-a-guide-for-students">Building Your Brand on LinkedIn: A Guide for Students</h2>

<p>In today’s digital age, building a personal brand is essential for career growth and professional development. One effective way to start is by leveraging LinkedIn, the world’s largest professional network. Inspired by John Stepper’s <em>Working Out Loud</em> principles, this guide will help you establish a strong presence on LinkedIn by following and engaging with thought leaders in your field.</p>

<h3 id="why-follow-thought-leaders">Why Follow Thought Leaders?</h3>

<p>Following thought leaders on LinkedIn can provide you with valuable insights, industry trends, and professional advice. These individuals are often at the forefront of their fields, sharing knowledge and experiences that can help you grow. By engaging with their content, you not only learn from the best but also increase your visibility and credibility within your network.</p>

<h3 id="steps-to-build-your-brand">Steps to Build Your Brand</h3>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Identify Thought Leaders</strong><br />
Use LinkedIn’s search and hashtags to discover respected professionals who frequently share relevant content in your area of interest.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Follow and Engage</strong><br />
Like, comment, and repost thoughtfully. Engaging with their content not only builds your knowledge but also puts you on their radar.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Repost with Insights</strong><br />
When sharing their posts, add a sentence or two about why the content matters to you. This shows you’re not just curating content, but learning from it.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Consistent Activity</strong><br />
Spend 10–15 minutes a few times a week reading, posting, and connecting. Consistency is key to staying visible and building credibility.</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<hr />

<h2 id="-exercise-chatgpt-follow-leaders">💡 Exercise: ChatGPT Follow Leaders</h2>

<h3 id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>This exercise encourages students to identify thought leaders in their field using ChatGPT. By researching and engaging with these leaders, students can expand their network and gain valuable insights.</p>

<h3 id="principle">Principle:</h3>
<p><strong>Engagement with thought leaders enhances learning and networking.</strong><br />
Connecting with industry leaders provides students with exposure to new ideas and professional pathways.</p>

<h3 id="why-included">Why Included:</h3>
<p>To help students identify individuals who can support their growth, and practice “Working Out Loud” by showing their learning in public.</p>

<hr />

<h3 id="️-how-to-perform-the-exercise">🛠️ How to Perform the Exercise</h3>

<ol>
  <li><strong>Use ChatGPT to Identify Leaders</strong><br />
Try prompts like:
    <ul>
      <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">"Create a table of thought leaders that are sales engineers. List the thought leader and what they are famous for."</code></li>
      <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">"Which thought leader is respected by Microsoft employees?"</code></li>
      <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">"As an undergraduate with no work experience, how can I network with Tiffani Bova on LinkedIn to get access to Microsoft leaders?"</code></li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Research and Follow</strong><br />
Look up the people you discover. What do they post about? How can you join the conversation?</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Engage and Repost</strong><br />
Start small: like and comment. Then repost with a short insight. Build your confidence over time.</p>
  </li>
  <li><strong>Reflect and Connect</strong><br />
Reach out with a short message like, <em>“Thanks for your post on [topic]—I’m a student learning about this field and found it super helpful.”</em> Personal, sincere messages go a long way.</li>
</ol>

<hr />

<p>By following these steps and incorporating the “ChatGPT Follow Leaders” exercise, you’ll be well on your way to building a strong personal brand on LinkedIn. Remember, the key to success is <strong>consistent engagement</strong> and <strong>adding value to your network</strong>.</p>

<p>Happy networking!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="career" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Students can build a professional brand on LinkedIn by following and engaging with thought leaders using John Stepper’s Working Out Loud principles and ChatGPT.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Explore Career Paths with ChatGPT</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/career/explore-career-paths-with-chatgpt/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Explore Career Paths with ChatGPT" /><published>2025-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/career/explore-career-paths-with-chatgpt</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/career/explore-career-paths-with-chatgpt/"><![CDATA[<h3 id="explore-career-paths-with-chatgpt-a-growth-mindset-exercise">Explore Career Paths with ChatGPT: A Growth Mindset Exercise</h3>

<p>College is the perfect time to explore possibilities, test ideas, and dream big about your future. But what if you’re not sure where to start—or you’re overwhelmed by all the options? This simple yet powerful exercise uses ChatGPT to help you brainstorm career paths, guided by your own interests, experiences, and strengths.</p>

<hr />

<h3 id="principle-exploration-leads-to-informed-decision-making">Principle: Exploration Leads to Informed Decision-Making</h3>

<p>The more you explore, the more you learn about yourself—and the more intentional your career decisions become. This exercise is built on the belief that curiosity and discovery unlock new opportunities that align with who you are and who you’re becoming.</p>

<hr />

<h3 id="why-this-exercise-matters">Why This Exercise Matters</h3>

<p>Using ChatGPT, you’ll tap into an incredible resource to:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Expand your awareness of industries and roles.</li>
  <li>Discover jobs you might not have considered.</li>
  <li>Align career options with your values and strengths.</li>
  <li>Start building a career map that’s personal and flexible.</li>
</ul>

<p>It’s also a great way to practice a <strong>growth mindset</strong>—believing that you can learn and grow through effort, feedback, and exploration.</p>

<hr />

<h3 id="exercise-brainstorm-career-paths-with-chatgpt">Exercise: Brainstorm Career Paths with ChatGPT</h3>

<h4 id="objective">Objective:</h4>
<p>To identify potential career paths that align with your interests, values, and goals—using ChatGPT as a research and brainstorming partner.</p>

<hr />

<h3 id="step-by-step-instructions">Step-by-Step Instructions</h3>

<h4 id="1-get-to-know-chatgpt">1. Get to Know ChatGPT</h4>
<p>ChatGPT is a conversational AI that can help you research jobs, brainstorm ideas, and explore career paths. It’s like having a smart assistant that’s available 24/7 to guide your thinking.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>🧠 Tip: Use clear, specific prompts to get the best results. The more context you provide, the better ChatGPT can help you.</p>
</blockquote>

<hr />

<h4 id="2-list-your-strengths-interests--experiences">2. List Your Strengths, Interests &amp; Experiences</h4>
<p>Before jumping into ChatGPT, take 5 minutes to jot down:</p>
<ul>
  <li>What you’re curious about</li>
  <li>What you enjoy doing</li>
  <li>What skills or experiences make you feel proud</li>
  <li>Clubs, internships, classes, or hobbies you’ve loved</li>
</ul>

<p>This reflection will help you craft better prompts—and recognize patterns that point toward possible career paths.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="3-try-these-chatgpt-prompts">3. Try These ChatGPT Prompts</h4>

<p>Here are a few examples to kick things off:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Career Ideas Based on Interests</strong>
    <blockquote>
      <p>“I have a passion for technology, sales, and finance. What kind of entry-level jobs are available to me after graduating college? Create a table that includes the job, a description, salary range, and career progression.”</p>
    </blockquote>
  </li>
  <li><strong>Top Companies</strong>
    <blockquote>
      <p>“What are the top companies that sales engineers work for? Create a table with company name, mission statement, location, and company size.”</p>
    </blockquote>
  </li>
  <li><strong>Professional Associations</strong>
    <blockquote>
      <p>“What are the associations that sales engineers who work at Amazon Web Services join? Create a table with the association name, mission, and opportunities for recent graduates.”</p>
    </blockquote>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>Feel free to change the prompts to reflect your own interests and goals!</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="4-analyze-the-results">4. Analyze the Results</h4>
<p>Look through the suggestions ChatGPT gives you. Ask yourself:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Which jobs or industries resonate with me?</li>
  <li>What patterns do I notice?</li>
  <li>Which career paths feel exciting, challenging, or meaningful?</li>
</ul>

<p>Take notes and highlight a few options that stand out.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="5-map-out-your-career-trajectory">5. Map Out Your Career Trajectory</h4>
<p>Pick one or two paths you’re excited about, and outline:</p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Short-term goals</strong> (What internships or classes can you take now?)</li>
  <li><strong>Mid-term steps</strong> (What jobs would you aim for after graduation?)</li>
  <li><strong>Long-term vision</strong> (Where do you want to be in 5–10 years?)</li>
</ul>

<p>Consider what skills or experiences you need to get there—and how you might build them over time.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="6-reflect-and-share">6. Reflect and Share</h4>
<p>Join a small group or discussion circle to:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Share what you learned from ChatGPT</li>
  <li>Get feedback on your ideas</li>
  <li>Encourage each other to keep exploring</li>
</ul>

<p>You’ll find that talking about your goals with others makes them feel more real—and gives you energy to keep moving forward.</p>

<hr />

<h3 id="embrace-the-growth-mindset">Embrace the Growth Mindset</h3>

<p>A growth mindset reminds you that your future isn’t set in stone—it’s shaped by your curiosity, effort, and willingness to learn. Career paths evolve. You’ll change, your interests will shift, and that’s okay. This exercise is just one step in a lifelong journey of discovery.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“The only way to discover the limits of the possible is to go beyond them into the impossible.” – Arthur C. Clarke</p>
</blockquote>

<hr />

<h3 id="final-thought">Final Thought</h3>

<p>You don’t have to figure everything out right now. But you <em>do</em> have to start somewhere. This exercise helps you take that first step with intention and confidence. Use ChatGPT as your exploration partner—and let your growth mindset lead the way.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="career" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Use what the internet knows. A hands-on, growth-oriented look at career planning. Foster exploration, curiosity, and strategic thinking.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Our GitHub Community</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/alerts/Github-Community/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Our GitHub Community" /><published>2025-04-05T06:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-04-05T06:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/alerts/Github-Community</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/alerts/Github-Community/"><![CDATA[<p>We are thrilled to announce the launch of our new <a href="https://github.com/SujeethFoundation/sujeethfoundation.github.io/wiki">GitHub community</a>! This platform is designed to bring together passionate individuals who are eager to collaborate, share knowledge, and contribute to our mission help unlock the opportunity of education for every college student.</p>

<h2 id="purpose-of-the-github-community">Purpose of the GitHub Community</h2>

<p>Our GitHub community aims to:</p>

<ol>
  <li><strong>Foster Collaboration</strong>: By providing a space where members can share best practices, discuss challenges, and exchange resources, we hope to harness the power of collective wisdom.</li>
  <li><strong>Share Knowledge</strong>: This community will serve as a repository of valuable insights, tutorials, and best practices that can help everyone improve their skills and knowledge.</li>
  <li><strong>Encourage Innovation</strong>: We believe that by bringing together diverse perspectives, we can drive innovation and create solutions that make a real impact.</li>
  <li><strong>Support Our Mission</strong>: Every contribution made in this community will directly support our mission of empowering students to take ownership of their career journey and achieve meaningful employment.</li>
</ol>

<h2 id="how-you-can-participate">How You Can Participate</h2>

<p>We encourage everyone to get involved in our GitHub community. Here are a few ways you can participate:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Join Discussions</strong>: Engage in conversations, ask questions, and share your insights on various topics.</li>
  <li><strong>Share Best Practices</strong>: Contribute your experiences and strategies to help others succeed.</li>
  <li><strong>Discuss Challenges</strong>: Openly discuss the challenges you face and collaborate with others to find solutions.</li>
  <li><strong>Provide Resources</strong>: Share valuable tools, articles, and resources that can benefit the community.</li>
  <li><strong>Offer Feedback</strong>: Your feedback is crucial in helping us improve and evolve. Don’t hesitate to share your thoughts and suggestions.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="why-your-participation-matters">Why Your Participation Matters</h2>

<p>Your involvement in our GitHub community is vital. By participating, you’re not only helping us achieve our mission but also contributing to a larger movement of collaboration and innovation. Together, we can create something truly remarkable.</p>

<h2 id="key-sections">Key Sections</h2>
<div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
    <i class="fa fa-info-circle"></i> <b>Note:</b>
    Below are the key sections of the GitHub Community and an abstract of the content housed there.  Visit the community for comprehensive details about the Career Circle Program.
</div>
<p><br /></p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="https://github.com/SujeethFoundation/sujeethfoundation.github.io/wiki/Program-Overview%3A">Program Overview</a>: Goals and structure of the Career Circle Program.</li>
  <li><a href="#faq-for-mentors">FAQ for Mentors</a>: FAQ for mentors.</li>
  <li><a href="https://github.com/SujeethFoundation/sujeethfoundation.github.io/wiki/Weekly-Content%3A">Weekly Content</a>: Detailed breakdown of each week’s objectives, agenda, and resources.</li>
  <li><a href="https://github.com/SujeethFoundation/sujeethfoundation.github.io/wiki/Additional-Resources%3A">Additional Resources</a>: Templates, videos, articles, and more.</li>
  <li><a href="https://github.com/SujeethFoundation/sujeethfoundation.github.io/discussions">Discussion Board</a>: Support and Best Practice Sharing.</li>
  <li><a href="https://github.com/SujeethFoundation/sujeethfoundation.github.io/discussions">University Circles Directory</a>: Directory of LinkedIn Groups and weekly session recordings.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="faq-for-mentors" class="linked-heading">
    <a href="#faq-for-mentors">#</a> FAQ for Mentors
</h3>
<p><a href="https://github.com/SujeethFoundation/sujeethfoundation.github.io/wiki/FAQ-for-Mentors">wiki</a></p>

<h2 id="general-program-info">General Program Info</h2>

<h3 id="q-what-is-the-career-circle-program">Q: What is the Career Circle Program?</h3>
<p>A: It’s a 6-week virtual program that helps students grow personally and professionally by developing job search skills. Each week, students engage in guided group discussions, videos, and exercises focused on topics like resumes, interviews, networking, and negotiations.  To learn more check out the [[Program Overview:]]</p>

<h3 id="q-who-is-the-program-for">Q: Who is the program for?</h3>
<p>A: Students, especially those starting to explore internships or their first full-time job.</p>

<h3 id="q-what-happens-each-week">Q: What happens each week?</h3>
<p>A: Each session lasts one hour and includes group discussions, reflection exercises, videos, and practical skills. Each week focuses on a different theme, like self-assessment, job applications, and follow-up strategies.</p>

<h3 id="q-who-can-volunteer-with-the-sujeeth-foundation">Q: Who can volunteer with the Sujeeth Foundation?</h3>
<p>A: Volunteers are professional with 10 years of work experience, have a validated LinkedIn profile, and a commitment to mentorship.  You can apply to volunteer at: https://portal.sujeeth.org/volunteer.</p>

<h3 id="q-how-can-i-donate-to-the-sujeeth-foundation">Q: How can I donate to the Sujeeth Foundation?</h3>
<p>A: Anyone can donate to the Sujeeth Foundation at the foundations GoFundMe page: https://go.sujeeth.org/give</p>

<h3 id="q-who-are-sujeeth-foundation-partners">Q: Who are Sujeeth Foundation Partners?</h3>
<p>A: The Sujeeth Foundation partners with accredited non-profit institutions, colleges, and universities.  You can find out more about partnering with the Sujeeth Foundation at https://www.sujeeth.org/partner.</p>

<hr />

<h2 id="working-with-students">Working with Students</h2>

<h3 id="q-who-are-the-students">Q: Who are the students?</h3>
<p>A: These are college students. They are seeking support, guidance, and mentorship to help them navigate their career journeys.</p>

<h3 id="q-can-i-reach-out-to-students-outside-of-the-sessions">Q: Can I reach out to students outside of the sessions?</h3>
<p>A: We encourage mentors to connect with students on LinkedIn or through the program’s group discussions.</p>

<h3 id="q-do-i-need-to-impress-the-students">Q: Do I need to impress the students?</h3>
<p>A: Not at all. It’s about creating a supportive and learning-focused environment. The goal is to be genuine, share your experiences, and help them with their career development.</p>

<hr />

<h2 id="session-logistics">Session Logistics</h2>

<h3 id="q-how-do-i-join-the-sessions">Q: How do I join the sessions?</h3>
<p>A: After signing up, you’ll receive Teams links and calendar invites for each session. Make sure to show up on time and engage in the discussions.</p>

<h3 id="q-what-if-i-miss-a-session">Q: What if I miss a session?</h3>
<p>A: It’s important to attend as much as possible. If you my miss a session, please submit a <a href="https://portal.sujeeth.org/circle/coverage">coverage request</a> so we can try to get you a substitute.  Above all communicate!  Reach out to the program facilitators for updates.</p>

<h3 id="q-do-i-need-to-prepare-anything-before-the-sessions">Q: Do I need to prepare anything before the sessions?</h3>
<p>A: Yes! All of our material is published and available to review before the session, such as videos or reflection questions. This helps you contribute more effectively to the discussion.  Check out [[Program Overview:]] for more information.</p>

<hr />

<h2 id="during-the-sessions">During the Sessions</h2>

<h3 id="q-how-can-i-best-support-the-students">Q: How can I best support the students?</h3>
<p>A: Encourage open communication, share personal stories, and provide constructive feedback. Be empathetic to their challenges and create a comfortable space for them to ask questions.</p>

<h3 id="q-what-should-i-do-if-a-student-seems-unsure-or-nervous">Q: What should I do if a student seems unsure or nervous?</h3>
<p>A: Be patient and understanding. It’s normal for students to feel nervous in new environments. Offer reassurance and encourage them to share their thoughts when they feel ready.</p>

<h3 id="q-will-i-be-expected-to-grade-or-evaluate-the-students">Q: Will I be expected to grade or evaluate the students?</h3>
<p>A: No, you won’t grade or formally evaluate students. Your role is to offer mentorship and guidance, sharing feedback and insights based on your experience.</p>

<hr />

<h2 id="making-the-most-of-the-program">Making the Most of the Program</h2>

<h3 id="q-how-can-i-make-the-most-of-this-mentorship-experience">Q: How can I make the most of this mentorship experience?</h3>
<p>A: Engage in the discussions, share relevant experiences, ask questions that prompt critical thinking, and be available for follow-up outside the sessions if needed. Mentorship is about creating a lasting impact, even if it’s just one small piece of advice.</p>

<h3 id="q-how-do-i-ensure-that-the-students-feel-supported-throughout-the-program">Q: How do I ensure that the students feel supported throughout the program?</h3>
<p>A: Be consistent and available. Check in with students outside the sessions, offer encouragement, and help them set actionable goals. Show them that you care about their growth, not just the program.</p>

<h3 id="q-what-are-ways-i-can-volunteer-for-the-sujeeth-foundation">Q: What are ways I can volunteer for the Sujeeth Foundation?</h3>
<p>A: Being a mentor is the primary that people volunteer with the Foundation.  In addition, there are limited opportunities to manage school relationships, the volunteer community, donor engagement, or the foundation’s overall social media strategy.   Reach out to the program facilitators for more information.</p>

<hr />

<h2 id="still-have-questions">Still Have Questions?</h2>
<p>Ask them on the <a href="https://github.com/SujeethFoundation/sujeethfoundation.github.io/discussions">discussion board</a>. We’re here to support you in making the most of your mentoring experience.</p>

<p><a href="https://github-wiki-see.page/m/SujeethFoundation/sujeethfoundation.github.io/wiki">Crawlable Wiki</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="alerts" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The volunteer experience is brought together by our Github Community. The wiki and discussion board make it easy to share knowledge. Key Sections include a FAQ, the Career Circle Program Structure and Weekly Agenda's. There's even an inventory of content that clearly explains the purpose behind the content.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Stepping Stones: Will Kyle</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Will-Kyle/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Stepping Stones: Will Kyle" /><published>2025-03-06T06:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-06T06:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Will-Kyle</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Will-Kyle/"><![CDATA[<p>The Sujeeth Foundation Spotlight highlights the stories of individuals who made the jump from academia to industry.  We share stories to inspire and educate.  We hope students can leverage this experience in their own journey.</p>

<p>Navigating a career path can be daunting for college juniors looking ahead to life after graduation. With uncertainty, competition, and the challenge of finding the right fit, it’s easy to feel overwhelmed. But stories of success can inspire and guide us—and Will Kyle’s journey from an entry-level sales job to leading a team at Amazon Web Services (AWS) is one of perseverance, adaptability, and growth.</p>

<h1 id="starting-out-the-first-job-that-built-a-foundation">Starting Out: The First Job That Built a Foundation</h1>
<p>Will Kyle’s first job out of college was far from glamorous—selling steel buildings. It wasn’t his dream job, nor was it in an industry he was particularly passionate about, but it was an opportunity to gain experience, develop his skills, and prove himself in the professional world.</p>

<p>At the time, the economy was in a recession, making job opportunities scarce. Will applied to any and every sales role he could find. After spotting an ad online for a steel building company, he took the leap. His role involved managing a network of steel building dealers, prospecting new customers, and running advertising campaigns. The company was resistant to technology, forcing him to work without the efficiencies of modern tools. Yet, instead of seeing this as a setback, he saw it as a learning experience.</p>

<p>With no structured training in sales, Will took ownership of his own professional development. He read books, sought mentorship, and pushed himself out of his comfort zone. The key lesson? Success is rarely handed to you—it’s something you must actively pursue.</p>

<div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
    <i class="fa fa-info-circle"></i> <b>Note:</b>
    Lesson - Start Somewhere, Grow Everywhere: Your first job doesn’t have to be your dream job—it’s a stepping stone to build skills, gain experience, and prove yourself in the professional world.
</div>
<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="climbing-the-ladder-wills-career-at-amazon-and-aws">Climbing the Ladder: Will’s Career at Amazon and AWS</h2>
<p>Will’s persistence and commitment to learning paved the way for his entry into major corporate roles. He spent have spent 12 years at Amazon, 8 years in ecommerce and 4 years at AWS.</p>

<p>Today, as an Enterprise Sales Leader at AWS, Will is responsible for business planning, consultative selling, and leading high-impact initiatives. Over the past four years at AWS, he has excelled in multiple roles, including Senior Account Executive, where he leveraged his deep expertise in sales presentations and strategic client engagement.</p>

<p>His career at AWS has given him the opportunity to lead a team of professionals, drive enterprise growth, and work at the cutting edge of cloud technology. Most importantly, he has continued to develop his passion for mentorship—helping individuals advance their careers both within and outside of Amazon.</p>

<h2 id="lessons-from-the-journey-building-a-network-and-asking-for-help">Lessons from the Journey: Building a Network and Asking for Help</h2>
<p>Reflecting on his career, Will emphasizes the importance of networking and mentorship. “Every single person you meet is an opportunity to expand your network. Never burn a bridge,” he advises. Throughout his career, he has found that there are always people willing to help—but it’s up to you to ask for guidance. Taking initiative in building relationships and seeking mentorship can be game-changing.</p>

<div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
    <i class="fa fa-info-circle"></i> <b>Note:</b>
    Lesson - Invest in Relationships: Never burn bridges—connections can help you advance, and relationships play a key role in professional growth.
</div>
<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="advice-for-college-juniors-the-first-job-is-just-a-stepping-stone">Advice for College Juniors: The First Job is Just a Stepping Stone</h2>
<p>For college juniors about to embark on their professional journeys, Will offers one crucial piece of advice: Be patient and focus on building experience.</p>

<p>Your first job out of school doesn’t have to be your dream job. It’s a stepping stone—a chance to learn, build skills, and prove yourself to future employers. Instead of limiting yourself to roles that seem perfect, embrace opportunities that allow you to grow. Your passions and goals will evolve over time, and the most important thing is to keep moving forward.</p>

<p>Will Kyle’s career path is a testament to the power of resilience, continuous learning, and strategic networking. Whether you’re a college junior trying to find direction or an early-career professional seeking motivation, his story serves as a reminder that every experience—no matter how small—can be a building block for future success.</p>

<p>Stay open to opportunities, invest in relationships, and never stop learning. Your journey is just beginning.</p>

<p>We’d love to spot light you.  Tell us your story at <a href="https://www.sujeeth.org/stories">https://www.sujeeth.org/stories</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="spotlight" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Will Kyle shares how perseverance, mentorship, and strategic networking helped him navigate challenges and achieve success in his journey from selling steel buildings to becoming an Enterprise Sales Leader at AWS. Learn practical tips for students on building experience, embracing opportunities, and making the most of their first job.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Find Your Why: Valerie Bergman</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Valerie-Bergman/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Find Your Why: Valerie Bergman" /><published>2025-03-06T06:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-06T06:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Valerie-Bergman</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Valerie-Bergman/"><![CDATA[<p>The Sujeeth Foundation Spotlight highlights the stories of individuals who made the jump from academia to industry.  We share stories to inspire and educate.  We hope students can leverage this experience in their own journey.</p>

<p>As students begin to navigate the bridge between academics and career aspirations, it can feel like an overwhelming journey. Questions about the right first job, long-term goals, and personal fulfillment often weigh heavily on students. That’s why we’re thrilled to spotlight <strong>Valerie Bergman</strong>, a Field Sales Specialist for Data and AI in Azure at Microsoft, whose career journey offers both inspiration and practical advice.</p>

<p>Valerie Bergman’s career spans over 20 years, from starting as a software engineer to becoming a Data &amp; AI Specialist at Microsoft. Along the way, she led IT strategy at Avtex Solutions, guided enterprise customers as a technology strategist, and now helps businesses innovate with AI and data solutions. Her journey reflects a focus on solving problems, driving innovation, and mentoring future STEM leaders.</p>

<h2 id="aligning-passion-with-profession">Aligning Passion with Profession</h2>
<p>Valerie’s current role at Microsoft combines her technical expertise with her passion for helping others. She thrives on solving complex problems and helping her customers justify their investments in innovation. Her journey exemplifies the Japanese concept of <strong>Ikigai</strong>, or “reason for being,” as she’s managed to align her passion, mission, vocation, and profession.</p>

<p>Valerie’s story is a testament to the importance of finding work that resonates deeply with your skills and values. She believes that career success isn’t just about the “how” but about understanding the “<strong>why</strong>”—a lesson that has guided her throughout her career.</p>

<h2 id="the-first-career-step">The First Career Step</h2>
<p>Valerie’s career began as a software engineer for a consulting company, where she developed custom software. This experience was pivotal in shaping her career trajectory. “I learned so much about technology in school, but my first job kickstarted my passion for understanding business requirements and opportunities,” Valerie recalls.</p>

<p>One of her key takeaways from this early experience was the importance of focusing on <strong>why, who, and what</strong> before jumping into the <strong>how</strong>. “Too often, failure happens because the ‘why’ is not fully understood,” she notes.</p>

<h2 id="strategies-that-work">Strategies That Work</h2>
<p>Landing her first job was no accident. Valerie credits a combination of <strong>networking</strong>, building an <strong>online brand</strong>, and leveraging <strong>job postings</strong> as strategies that helped her break into the tech industry. Her experience underscores the importance of being proactive and using multiple approaches when job hunting.</p>

<h2 id="lessons-from-the-journey">Lessons from the Journey</h2>
<p>Valerie’s career journey has been shaped by valuable insights and mindset shifts, such as:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Always seek to understand <strong>why</strong> before tackling how.</li>
  <li>Don’t shy away from failure; view it as a stepping stone, not a permanent setback.</li>
  <li>Keep learning and stay curious.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="college-experience-a-foundation-for-growth">College Experience: A Foundation for Growth</h2>
<p>For Valerie, college wasn’t just about academics—it was also about preparing for the real world. While working her way through school, she developed critical time-management skills and gained early career exposure. However, Valerie also emphasizes the importance of engaging with the <strong>social aspects of college life</strong>, as these experiences help build networks and develop interpersonal skills.</p>

<h2 id="words-of-wisdom-for-the-next-generation">Words of Wisdom for the Next Generation</h2>
<p>Valerie’s advice for students is both simple and profound:</p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Always have fun.</strong> Find joy in what you do, no matter where you are in your career.</li>
  <li><strong>Be courageous.</strong> Take risks and lean into challenges.</li>
  <li><strong>Never compromise who you are.</strong> Authenticity is key to long-term success.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="a-final-thought">A Final Thought</h2>
<p>Valerie Bergman’s journey shows that a fulfilling career is about more than just landing a job—it’s about aligning your skills, passions, and values. For college juniors planning their futures, her story serves as a powerful reminder to focus on the “why” behind their career choices, embrace continuous learning, and take bold steps toward their goals.</p>

<p>Let Valerie’s advice be your guide as you embark on your career journey—and remember, every failed attempt is simply a stepping stone toward success.</p>

<p>We’d love to spot light you.  Tell us your story at <a href="https://www.sujeeth.org/stories">https://www.sujeeth.org/stories</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="spotlight" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Valerie Bergman aligned passion with profession, strategic networking, and continuous learning on her inspiring journey from software engineer to Microsoft Field Sales Specialist. Get practical advice on building experience, embracing challenges, and staying authentic.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Yes Now, Learn It Later: Britt Hall</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Britt-Hall/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Yes Now, Learn It Later: Britt Hall" /><published>2025-03-06T06:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-06T06:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Britt-Hall</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Britt-Hall/"><![CDATA[<p>The Sujeeth Foundation Spotlight highlights the stories of individuals who made the jump from academia to industry.  We share stories to inspire and educate.  We hope students can leverage this experience in their own journey.</p>

<p>For many college juniors, the uncertainty of what comes next can be overwhelming. You might be wondering if your major is the right fit, how to land your first job, or whether the twists and turns of your journey will lead to success. To offer some inspiration, we’re sharing the story of Britt Hall—a professional who carved out a fulfilling career by embracing change, saying “yes” to opportunities, and staying true to their values.</p>

<p>Britt Hall’s career has been a journey of transformation, adaptability, and storytelling. She began in journalism, leading student newspapers and shaping narratives that connected communities. That passion for communication and culture led her into corporate environments, where she built internal communications strategies, fostered engagement, and helped organizations navigate change.</p>

<p>At Whole Foods Market, Britt played a key role in launching the 365 brand, designing team member experiences and driving internal culture. At National Instruments, she partnered with senior leaders to implement large-scale transformation and modern workplace initiatives. Now, at Cisco, she leads global enablement efforts, ensuring talent strategies empower people and teams to thrive.</p>

<p>Through every step, Britt’s work has been shaped by three guiding values: authenticity, accountability, and creative problem-solving. She remains dedicated to building meaningful experiences that drive impact.</p>

<h2 id="the-first-steps-a-nonlinear-college-journey">The First Steps: A Nonlinear College Journey</h2>
<p>Britt Hall’s college experience wasn’t a straight path. In fact, it took nearly seven years to complete a bachelor’s degree. Initially pursuing music education and performance, Britt found themselves on an expected trajectory—until a single elective, “Storytelling and Puppetry,” reshaped their perspective. That class ignited a passion for storytelling, leading to a major shift into journalism and communications.</p>

<p>Switching from a music program meant starting over, even taking a step back to community college before transferring again on a journalism scholarship. These experiences taught Britt valuable lessons in resilience, adaptability, and trusting one’s instincts—skills that would prove crucial in their career.</p>

<h2 id="the-first-job-freelance-hustle-and-saying-yes">The First Job: Freelance, Hustle, and Saying Yes</h2>
<p>Britt’s first job after college wasn’t handed to them—it was built through experience and opportunity. While freelancing for the Corpus Christi Caller-Times, Britt wore many hats: general assignments reporter, copy editor, and even interim archivist. At the same time, they worked as a barista, eventually taking on training and marketing roles for the coffee shop.</p>

<p>Three months after graduation, Britt secured their first full-time role in marketing and communications for the Corpus Christi Symphony Orchestra—an opportunity that came from an earlier internship. The key lesson? Keep doors open, maintain good relationships, and recognize that every experience (even in retail and food service) builds skills that matter.</p>

<div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
    <i class="fa fa-info-circle"></i> <b>Note:</b>
    Lesson - Strengthen relationships: Networking and maintaining connections are crucial for career growth, as Britt’s first full-time job stemmed from an internship.
</div>
<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="a-career-built-on-passion-and-adaptability">A Career Built on Passion and Adaptability</h2>
<p>Fast forward to today, Britt leads a global team at Cisco, managing employee experience and enablement for hiring and internal talent movement programs. It’s a role that aligns almost perfectly with their Ikigai—the Japanese concept of purpose—combining passion, mission, vocation, and profession.</p>

<p>Britt’s journey from journalism to corporate leadership wasn’t accidental. It was guided by a mindset of embracing change, being willing to “figure it out,” and leveraging past experiences to build a unique and valuable career path.</p>

<div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
    <i class="fa fa-info-circle"></i> <b>Note:</b>
    Lesson - Identify your values early: Britt’s principles—authenticity, accountability, and creative problem-solving—shaped their career decisions and work-life balance.
</div>
<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="advice-for-college-juniors-be-a-bricoleur">Advice for College Juniors: Be a Bricoleur</h2>
<p>So, what advice does Britt have for students entering the workforce?</p>
<ol>
  <li><strong>Say yes now, figure it out later.</strong> Opportunities don’t always come neatly packaged. Trust yourself enough to take on challenges, even when you don’t feel fully prepared.</li>
  <li><strong>Build resilience.</strong> The most adaptable and successful people share three traits: accepting reality, finding meaning in what they do, and improvising when necessary.</li>
  <li><strong>Identify your values early.</strong> Britt’s guiding principles—authenticity, accountability, and creative problem-solving—help in making decisions, setting boundaries, and maintaining work-life balance.</li>
  <li><strong>Keep relationships strong.</strong> The first full-time job came from an internship, and career growth often hinges on connections and a strong reputation.</li>
</ol>

<h2 id="the-takeaway-your-path-is-yours-to-make">The Takeaway: Your Path is Yours to Make</h2>
<p>Britt Hall’s career isn’t one of rigid planning—it’s a testament to adaptability, lifelong learning, and saying “yes” to the right opportunities. For college juniors feeling uncertain, the message is clear: your path doesn’t have to be linear. Trust the journey, embrace change, and build a career that aligns with your passions and strengths.</p>

<p>So, as you plan your next steps, remember—you have the power to shape your own story, just like Britt Hall did.</p>

<p>We’d love to spot light you.  Tell us your story at <a href="https://www.sujeeth.org/stories">https://www.sujeeth.org/stories</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="spotlight" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Britt Hall's adaptability, resilience, and strategic networking took her from journalism to corporate leadership. Discover practical tips for students on building experience, embracing change, and aligning their careers with their passions and strengths.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Prepare and Adapt: Dave D’Abate</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Dave-Dabate/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Prepare and Adapt: Dave D’Abate" /><published>2025-03-06T06:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-06T06:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Dave-Dabate</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Dave-Dabate/"><![CDATA[<p>The Sujeeth Foundation Spotlight highlights the stories of individuals who made the jump from academia to industry.  We share stories to inspire and educate.  We hope students can leverage this experience in their own journey.</p>

<p>For college juniors preparing to launch their careers, the path ahead can feel both exciting and uncertain. How do you land that first job? What skills truly matter? How do you turn a job into a fulfilling career? To help answer these questions, we spoke with Dave D’Abate, a successful Account Executive whose career journey is proof that relationships, continuous learning, and adaptability are key ingredients for long-term success.</p>

<h2 id="starting-strong-lessons-from-the-first-job">Starting Strong: Lessons from the First Job</h2>
<p>Dave’s career began at AT&amp;T as a retail sales consultant. Like many fresh graduates, he started in an entry-level role, selling devices and services to both consumers and small business accounts. But what set him apart? His mindset. While others simply met expectations, Dave aimed higher—doubling his sales targets and positioning himself as a go-to resource and subject matter expert.</p>

<p>He quickly learned that success isn’t just about showing up; it’s about being proactive. “I had to put in the effort beyond what I witnessed from my colleagues,” he says. This willingness to go the extra mile became a defining trait in his career.</p>

<div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
    <i class="fa fa-info-circle"></i> <b>Note:</b>
    Lesson - Starting Strong: Success in a first job requires a proactive mindset and a willingness to exceed expectations. Dave excelled by doubling his sales targets and establishing himself as a subject matter expert.
</div>
<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="breaking-into-the-workforce-the-power-of-first-impressions">Breaking into the Workforce: The Power of First Impressions</h2>
<p>Landing that first job can be daunting, but Dave emphasizes the importance of energy, enthusiasm, and preparation. One piece of advice he received early on has stuck with him: “Every conversation you have is an interview.” From the very first screening call to the final handshake, the way you present yourself matters. Being able to articulate your work ethic and passion can make all the difference in standing out to hiring managers.</p>

<h2 id="building-a-career-key-lessons-and-mindset-shifts">Building a Career: Key Lessons and Mindset Shifts</h2>
<p>Over the years, Dave has picked up several insights that have fueled his success:</p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Be willing to learn.</strong> Taking the extra time to do something correctly now will set you up for success later.</li>
  <li><strong>Manage your business.</strong> If something needs to get done, schedule time for it—otherwise, it won’t happen.</li>
  <li><strong>Adaptability is key.</strong> You won’t always succeed on the first try, but the ability to adjust and improve will make you stronger.</li>
  <li><strong>Incorporate feedback immediately.</strong> When someone offers guidance, show them that their investment in you is worth it by implementing changes right away.</li>
</ul>

<div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
    <i class="fa fa-info-circle"></i> <b>Note:</b>
    Lesson - Investing in Success: Actively seek mentors, apply their knowledge, and maintain a commitment to lifelong learning. If you’re the smartest in the room, challenge yourself to grow by seeking new opportunities.
</div>
<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="from-college-to-career-the-importance-of-preparation">From College to Career: The Importance of Preparation</h2>
<p>Dave admits that he wasn’t the best student in college—he spent more time hiking than studying. But he quickly realized that preparation is everything. “Studying in college is very similar to how one should prepare before any meeting,” he explains. Whether it’s a class or a client presentation, showing up unprepared is never an option. Observing how others operate and borrowing their best practices can help you refine your own approach over time.</p>

<h2 id="final-advice-for-students-entering-the-workforce">Final Advice for Students Entering the Workforce</h2>
<p>Dave’s parting wisdom for students is simple yet powerful: “Always set aside time to continue investing in your success.” Seek out mentors who are invested in your growth, absorb their knowledge, and apply it. But never stop learning—if you ever find yourself as the smartest person in the room, it’s time to find a different room.</p>

<p>As you chart your own career path, remember that success isn’t a straight line. It’s built on hard work, adaptability, and the relationships you nurture along the way. Take a page from Dave D’Abate’s journey, and embrace every opportunity to learn and grow.</p>

<p>We’d love to spot light you.  Tell us your story at <a href="https://www.sujeeth.org/stories">https://www.sujeeth.org/stories</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="spotlight" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dave D'Abate relied on relationships, continuous learning, and adaptability to go from retail sales consultant at AT&T to Account Executive. Discover practical tips for students on building experience, embracing challenges, and navigating their career paths effectively.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Start Small: Laurel Dzneladze</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Laurel-Dzneladze/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Start Small: Laurel Dzneladze" /><published>2025-03-06T06:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-06T06:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Laurel-Dzneladze</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Laurel-Dzneladze/"><![CDATA[<p>The Sujeeth Foundation Spotlight highlights the stories of individuals who made the jump from academia to industry.  We share stories to inspire and educate.  We hope students can leverage this experience in their own journey.</p>

<p>Planning your career might seem daunting, but learning from those who have navigated similar paths can be both inspiring and insightful. One such story is that of Laurel Dzneladze, a dynamic professional at Microsoft whose journey showcases the power of adaptability, networking, and continuous learning.</p>

<h2 id="finding-passion-through-experience">Finding Passion Through Experience</h2>
<p>Laurel currently supports the Microsoft Viva Community and communication products, focusing on product marketing and go-to-market strategies. Her passion lies in how community and communications shape an organization’s success. Throughout her career, she has dedicated herself to building solutions that drive engagement, productivity, and overall success within companies.</p>

<p>Her career trajectory wasn’t a straight line, but each experience helped shape her professional path. Laurel’s story is proof that discovering your Ikigai—the intersection of passion, mission, vocation, and profession—takes time, experimentation, and a willingness to explore different opportunities.</p>

<div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
    <i class="fa fa-info-circle"></i> <b>Note:</b>
    Lesson - Adaptability and Nonlinear Paths: Laurel’s career path and academic journey were unconventional, showing that flexibility and persistence can lead to success. Careers don’t have to follow a straight line, and varied experiences can become valuable assets.
</div>
<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="from-internship-to-full-time-success">From Internship to Full-Time Success</h2>
<p>Laurel’s first job came as an extension of an internship at Johnson Controls, which transitioned into a full-time role after graduation. In this position, she was responsible for communicating large organizational changes and managing digital spaces like the company’s website and intranet.
Some of her most valuable lessons from this early experience included:</p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Understanding organizational processes</strong>—how to start and complete a project effectively.</li>
  <li><strong>Developing presentation and executive relationship skills</strong>—key abilities that help in gaining visibility and trust.</li>
  <li><strong>Collaborating in a corporate environment</strong>—learning how to navigate teams and work cross-functionally.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="landing-the-first-job-a-lesson-in-proactive-networking">Landing the First Job: A Lesson in Proactive Networking</h2>
<p>How did Laurel secure her internship that led to her first job? It started with an unpaid marketing role at a performing arts foundation, where she dedicated just four hours a week. That experience gave her exposure to a network of professionals, including board members who later connected her with the internship opportunity at Johnson Controls.
Her journey highlights a crucial strategy:</p>
<blockquote>
  <p>Start small, be proactive, and leverage networking opportunities. Even the smallest roles can lead to significant career breakthroughs when approached with the right mindset.</p>
</blockquote>

<h2 id="career-lessons-and-mindset-shifts">Career Lessons and Mindset Shifts</h2>
<p>Throughout her career, Laurel has embraced a mindset of continuous learning and adaptability. Here are some of her key insights:</p>
<ol>
  <li><strong>Share ideas early and often</strong>—don’t be afraid to put your thoughts out there.</li>
  <li><strong>Ask questions instead of disagreeing outright</strong>—a great approach to constructive discussions.</li>
  <li><strong>Observe and learn from leadership</strong>—find role models whose work ethic and leadership style resonate with you.</li>
  <li><strong>Look beyond your immediate team</strong>—seek projects outside your role that expose you to new challenges and learning opportunities.</li>
</ol>

<h2 id="embracing-a-nonlinear-path">Embracing a Nonlinear Path</h2>
<p>Laurel’s college experience was anything but conventional. She started as a dance major in Kansas City, studied abroad for a year, then took time off before resuming college at 25 years old. She compressed 2.5 years of coursework into just 1.5 years, proving that determination and flexibility can reshape one’s academic and career path.</p>

<p>This unconventional journey reinforced an important lesson: careers are not always linear. The skills and experiences you gain from varied paths can become assets in unexpected ways.</p>

<div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
    <i class="fa fa-info-circle"></i> <b>Note:</b>
    Lesson - Clarifying Career Goals Through Experience: It’s okay to change your career direction multiple times. What matters is gaining clarity about what excites you and where you want to grow after exploring different roles.
</div>
<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="advice-for-college-students">Advice for College Students</h2>
<p>If Laurel could give one piece of advice to students entering the workforce, it would be:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Not every role needs to be your dream job, and not every company needs to be your dream company.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>It’s okay to change your mind about your career direction multiple times. What matters is gaining clarity on what excites you and where you want to grow after spending time in the workforce.</p>

<p>Takeaways for Your Career Journey
Laurel Dzneladze’s story is a testament to the power of <strong>persistence, adaptability, and strategic networking</strong>. Whether you’re just starting out or rethinking your path, remember that <strong>every experience adds value</strong>—even the unexpected ones. Your journey is uniquely yours, and with an open mind and proactive approach, you can carve a fulfilling and successful career.</p>

<p><strong>What’s your next step?</strong> Start small, be open to opportunities, and don’t be afraid to take the unconventional path—it might just lead you exactly where you need to be.</p>

<p>We’d love to spot light you.  Tell us your story at <a href="https://www.sujeeth.org/stories">https://www.sujeeth.org/stories</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="spotlight" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Laurel Dzneladze leveraged adaptability, networking, and continuous learning to go from an unpaid marketing role to a full-time position at Johnson Controls. Discover practical tips for students on building experience, embracing challenges, and navigating their career paths effectively.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Adaptability: Michelle Leaverton</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Michelle-Leaverton/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Adaptability: Michelle Leaverton" /><published>2025-03-06T06:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-06T06:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Michelle-Leaverton</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/spotlight/Spotlight-Michelle-Leaverton/"><![CDATA[<p>The Sujeeth Foundation Spotlight highlights the stories of individuals who made the jump from academia to industry.  We share stories to inspire and educate.  We hope students can leverage this experience in their own journey.</p>

<p>Some career paths are straightforward, while others, like Michelle Leaverton’s, weave through diverse industries and experiences, culminating in a skillset that defies categorization. From corporate project management to nonprofit leadership and ministry, Michelle’s journey exemplifies resilience, adaptability, and a deep commitment to making an impact.</p>

<h2 id="a-career-spanning-corporate-nonprofit-and-religious-sectors">A Career Spanning Corporate, Nonprofit, and Religious Sectors</h2>
<p>Michelle’s professional story is one of transformation and versatility. She recently held a role as an Advisor in Project and Program Management at Dell Technologies, where she worked in the Global Presales PMO. Over 2.5 years, she spearheaded global-scale enablement programs, process improvements, and career development initiatives for a workforce of over 5,000 professionals. Her ability to drive complex projects with creativity and collaboration made her an invaluable asset to the team.</p>

<p>Before Dell, Michelle dedicated much of her career to nonprofit and ministry work, reflecting her passion for community engagement and social impact. She served as the Youth and Social Impact Director at Westminster Presbyterian Church, where she designed and managed youth programs, mission trips, and outreach initiatives addressing food insecurity, homelessness, and immigrant support. Her leadership in coordinating volunteers for Meals on Wheels during the pandemic further demonstrated her ability to mobilize communities in times of need.</p>

<div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
    <i class="fa fa-info-circle"></i> <b>Note:</b>
    Lesson - Adaptability Across Sectors: Michelle’s career spans corporate, nonprofit, and religious sectors. Her success showcases the power of transferable skills and adaptability in navigating different industries.
</div>
<p><br /></p>
<h2 id="a-new-chapter-entrepreneurship-and-communication-expertise">A New Chapter: Entrepreneurship and Communication Expertise</h2>
<p>In August 2024, Michelle launched Collateral Designs, a business specializing in polished presentations and impactful communications. Her firm offers services that enhance clarity, creativity, and professionalism in business materials—helping clients craft compelling messages and visuals that stand out.</p>

<p>Michelle’s expertise in communication, project development, and strategic planning positions her uniquely at the intersection of corporate efficiency and nonprofit passion. She holds a Bachelor of Arts in Russian Studies and Environmental Studies from the University of Kansas and a Master of Arts in Christian Education from Union Presbyterian Seminary. Her diverse academic background underscores her ability to think across disciplines and adapt to new challenges.</p>

<h2 id="resilience-through-lifes-challenges">Resilience Through Life’s Challenges</h2>
<p>Beyond her professional achievements, Michelle’s personal journey is marked by resilience and growth. She and her husband, Rod, have spent the past decade rebuilding their lives after the loss of their first spouses to cancer. Through grief and joy, they’ve forged a new path, embracing life with their blended family and continuing to make a difference in the world.</p>

<h2 id="bringing-fresh-perspectives-to-every-opportunity">Bringing Fresh Perspectives to Every Opportunity</h2>
<p>Whether managing global programs, leading nonprofit initiatives, or helping businesses refine their messaging, Michelle Leaverton approaches every challenge with a problem-solving mindset. Her ability to adapt, learn, and lead across sectors is a testament to the power of a diverse career path.</p>

<div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
    <i class="fa fa-info-circle"></i> <b>Note:</b>
    Lesson - Diverse Perspectives: Her academic and professional diversity underpins her ability to think creatively and strategically.
</div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>If you’re looking for someone who can blend corporate strategy with a heart for mission-driven work, Michelle is a name to remember.</p>

<p>We’d love to spot light you.  Tell us your story at <a href="https://www.sujeeth.org/stories">https://www.sujeeth.org/stories</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="spotlight" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Michelle Leaverton showcased her resilience and adaptability as she transitioned from corporate project management at Dell Technologies to nonprofit leadership and ministry, and eventually launched her own business, Collateral Designs. Discover practical tips for students on building experience, embracing challenges, and making a positive impact in their professional lives.]]></summary></entry></feed>